<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?> <feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"> <title>Going The Wong Way</title> <link href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/> <link href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/"/> <updated>2016-12-08T20:33:31-08:00</updated> <id>http://www.goingthewongway.com</id> <author> <name>Derek Wong</name> <email>derek@goingthewongway.com</email> </author> <entry> <title>Monetary Gifts</title> <link href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/monetary-gifts/"/> <updated>2016-06-24T16:35:05-07:00</updated> <id>http://www.goingthewongway.com/monetary-gifts</id> <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Growing up (or I guess in general just being in want of money), people love to receive money as a gift. In some ways money is the ultimate gift because it can be applied to the purchase of anything. Only received $10? Well if you love technology then you can still save it towards the purchase of a new cell phone. That would be much more useful than some random $10 vase.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;On the other hand, I think that money can sometimes be a silly gift. I guess some people just don’t feel like it’s one of their &lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/28SnUpL&quot;&gt;love languages&lt;/a&gt; so they don’t see any merit in spending effort or time on it. More often than not people just pocket the money and forget who gave them what. For better or worse, you’d remember your great aunt if she gave you that $10 vase.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;By giving money, we go through life and essentially just move money around. We host an event and people give us money. We go to their events and give them money as well. We try to give an appropriate amount, which oftentimes is close to what they gave to us. So it seems like everyone ends up right where they started!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I dare not rant too hard against money or else I’m going to get cut out of the loop. So my method of handling this is to put any money that I receive into a separate “bucket” that gets earmarked for special purchases. When I save up enough money then I can buy something fun, and it feels like everyone chipped in and got a group gift. Perfect!&lt;/p&gt; </content> </entry> <entry> <title>Litter Bugs And Entitlement</title> <link href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/litter-bugs-and-entitlement/"/> <updated>2016-06-03T16:51:55-07:00</updated> <id>http://www.goingthewongway.com/litter-bugs-and-entitlement</id> <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of people out there who never learned about littering.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Who do they think is going to pick up their bags of fast food trash from the road? The “government”? Their parents? Or perhaps they’re just doing the world a service and allowing people to volunteer to help out their communities.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I can understand those that want to vote for “free” benefits for themselves. They’re just trying to get by with as little work as possible. I’m not saying that I agree.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;However, just like someone is actually paying for all of those “free” benefits (medical, welfare, food stamps, etc), someone is going to be picking up the fast food trash. So if someone doesn’t understand something as simple as picking up after themselves then I hardly think that they’re going to understand working for their own benefits.&lt;/p&gt; </content> </entry> <entry> <title>Cry Room Culture</title> <link href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/cry-room-culture/"/> <updated>2016-05-05T10:28:08-07:00</updated> <id>http://www.goingthewongway.com/cry-room-culture</id> <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Babies cry and make noise. This is no revelation. However it is still not socially acceptable for babies to cry and make noise everywhere that we go. It’s why we can’t take young children to nice dinners, the movies, or really anywhere that’s too expensive. Most recently this happened to us when &lt;a href=&quot;/the-bear-was-that-baby-on-the-plane/&quot;&gt;the Bear was crying on our flight&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;We don’t go on plane rides too often, but we do need to alter our social interactions at church every week. Our church is large enough that there’s a cry room that separates the parents with children (too young for the nursery) from the rest of the congregation. There are glass panels that allow the parents to participate without disturbing everyone else. Or so the theory goes.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The problem is that while it separates the babies from the congregation, it also separates the parents. This creates its own culture that is different from everyone else. It’s a culture where people don’t stand when everyone else stands, and people can talk when only the pastor is talking.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I can understand the thinking behind the cry room, but if I’m going to a church service then it’s not so that I can hear other parents chat. It’s really hard to concentrate or participate when you’re in the cry room (even if you &lt;em&gt;want&lt;/em&gt; to). I’m not saying that I can always pay attention now that I’m out of the cry room, but at least I won’t be tempted to blame other people now.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;On the other hand, I have no idea if going to a church service where the children sit with the parents is any better since I can only comment on what I’ve seen or experienced. And I’m sure that no matter what church you go to you will find people who will try to not participate (see &lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/1T3DTaj&quot;&gt;Everybody Loves Raymond season 4, episode 14 “Prodigal Son”&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt; </content> </entry> <entry> <title>The Bear Was THAT Baby On The Plane</title> <link href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/the-bear-was-that-baby-on-the-plane/"/> <updated>2016-04-12T09:21:22-07:00</updated> <id>http://www.goingthewongway.com/the-bear-was-that-baby-on-the-plane</id> <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We just traveled internationally with The Bear for the first time! It was generally fun, but the plane ride, oh the plane ride!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Going there wasn’t fun because she just wanted her mother the whole time. Coming back was even worse because we tried to get her to sleep when the cabin lights dimmed, and she didn’t like that. Actually she probably hated it. Screaming and wailing soon followed.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Nothing worked! We tried feeding her (magical) &lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/1Vk21oX&quot;&gt;puffs&lt;/a&gt;, singing, shushing, talking, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/1Vk25Fg&quot;&gt;ergo&lt;/a&gt;-ing. All we got in return was an assault on our ears and our chests (from baby fists). She was tired, but the only way that she ended up falling asleep was if I walked around and did NOT talk to her. It seemed that talking to her made her fussy again. I imagine that she protested because she knew that we were trying to get her to sleep. Her nap was a brief respite. She was only really comfortable sleeping when it was NOT sleep time (i.e., lights were turned on and people moving about).&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.gtww.net/2016/04_Japan/e3ir/sleep_dfji12.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Sleeping Bear&quot; title=&quot;The Bear CAN sleep&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; </content> </entry> <entry> <title>Sickness Strikes Again</title> <link href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/sickness-strikes-again/"/> <updated>2016-02-19T20:34:34-08:00</updated> <id>http://www.goingthewongway.com/sickness-strikes-again</id> <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have now been taken out by the Bear and her sicknesses twice within a span of 3 weeks. Considering I always thought of myself as a healthy and robust person, it’s no joke when they say that you should avoid having kids if you don’t want to get sick! It just goes to show you that none of us are really that strong. We’re really rather feeble and weak (despite our best intentions).&lt;/p&gt; </content> </entry> <entry> <title>The Sickness Is Strong In This One</title> <link href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/the-sickness-is-strong-in-this-one/"/> <updated>2016-01-29T16:23:46-08:00</updated> <id>http://www.goingthewongway.com/the-sickness-is-strong-in-this-one</id> <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Bear got sick this past week. It was bound to happen eventually, right? The illness came with a few bouts of vomit along with some rather unpleasant less-than-sleepful nights. All is as expected. Except that I was also infected with said illness!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;So I’m not saying that I don’t ever get sick. Because I do. I definitely do. In fact when I do get sick it seems like it’s extra awful. But it still catches me by surprise that I can get sick so easily by such a little baby. Conceptually I know that germs are much tinier than either of us, and size does not matter at all when getting sick. But something about it still surprises me.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Thankfully it only took me out for a day. But boy was it an unpleasant day!&lt;/p&gt; </content> </entry> <entry> <title>Colorado 2015</title> <link href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/colorado-2015/"/> <updated>2016-01-21T22:34:34-08:00</updated> <id>http://www.goingthewongway.com/colorado-2015</id> <content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;galleria&quot;&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://img.gtww.net/2015/11_Colorado/db3d/denver_co_springs-1_b343371.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-title=&quot;&quot; data-description=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://img.gtww.net/2015/11_Colorado/db3d/Thumbs/denver_co_springs-1_f568.jpg&quot; height=&quot;40&quot; width=&quot;33&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://img.gtww.net/2015/11_Colorado/db3d/denver_co_springs-2_3f90224.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-title=&quot;&quot; data-description=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://img.gtww.net/2015/11_Colorado/db3d/Thumbs/denver_co_springs-2_eb94.jpg&quot; height=&quot;40&quot; width=&quot;60&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://img.gtww.net/2015/11_Colorado/db3d/denver_co_springs-3_6445d04.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-title=&quot;&quot; data-description=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://img.gtww.net/2015/11_Colorado/db3d/Thumbs/denver_co_springs-3_8ceb.jpg&quot; height=&quot;40&quot; width=&quot;60&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://img.gtww.net/2015/11_Colorado/db3d/denver_co_springs-5_a19f7dc.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-title=&quot;&quot; data-description=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://img.gtww.net/2015/11_Colorado/db3d/Thumbs/denver_co_springs-5_baef.jpg&quot; height=&quot;40&quot; width=&quot;34&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://img.gtww.net/2015/11_Colorado/db3d/denver_co_springs-8_35f9894.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-title=&quot;&quot; data-description=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://img.gtww.net/2015/11_Colorado/db3d/Thumbs/denver_co_springs-8_0fa8.jpg&quot; height=&quot;40&quot; width=&quot;60&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;p&gt;It was our first time flying with a child, and it didn’t go too badly! Colorado had plenty of natural wonders, and it was nice to get out of the normal routine. In any case, you can also check out a few more pictures in the &lt;a href=&quot;/gallery/2015/colorado/&quot;&gt;gallery&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; </content> </entry> <entry> <title>Catching Poop</title> <link href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/catching-poop/"/> <updated>2016-01-14T10:57:16-08:00</updated> <id>http://www.goingthewongway.com/catching-poop</id> <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This post is vulgar and dirty (as many things in parenthood are). Just FYI.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;As I was changing the Bear’s diaper, she grabbed the changing pad (as she is wont to do). There was already some poop in the old diaper that I was changing so I moved that away before she could touch it. However, while I had her butt in the air (off of the changing table) she proceeded to poop some more. This new poop was fresh stuff (unlike the poop in the diaper which was more pebble-like). I was in a bind because one hand was holding up her legs, but the poop was going to land on the changing table. In order to save the poop from landing on the changing table, I had to just go for it. I decided that catching it with my hand was better than letting it fall.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;And thus I achieved another parenting milestone: I willingly chose to catch poop with my bare hand (thankfully not watery in any way).&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Ah parenthood, gotta love it.&lt;/p&gt; </content> </entry> <entry> <title>Moving Around (Or The Crawling Mischievous Bear)</title> <link href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/moving-around-or-the-crawling-mischievous-bear/"/> <updated>2015-12-30T15:27:02-08:00</updated> <id>http://www.goingthewongway.com/moving-around-or-the-crawling-mischievous-bear</id> <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Bear is starting to push herself backwards. Some might call it crawling, but others might laugh in their faces because it doesn’t look like crawling. She is also making it difficult to get our weekly picture. This means putting the props in her mouth, but more often it means knocking over blocks. Bothersome? Yes! Amusing? Yes, indeed!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.gtww.net/2015/12_Bear/b6b1/bear_7484fc0.jpg&quot; /&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;https://img.gtww.net/2015/12_Bear/b6b1/bear1_297ac06.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; </content> </entry> <entry> <title>What Do Kids Do With Their Hands?</title> <link href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/what-do-kids-do-with-their-hands/"/> <updated>2015-12-22T16:35:05-08:00</updated> <id>http://www.goingthewongway.com/what-do-kids-do-with-their-hands</id> <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Bear’s not even that mobile yet. Are we doomed? Probably, yes.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Things heard around my house much more now than pre-Bear:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;Hi! 😆&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;Where’s the poop?&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;Hey, get your hands out of there!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;How’d you get over there?&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/blockquote&gt; </content> </entry> <entry> <title>Migrating To Jekyll</title> <link href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/migrating-to-jekyll/"/> <updated>2015-12-17T22:20:28-08:00</updated> <id>http://www.goingthewongway.com/migrating-to-jekyll</id> <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I’m migrating this blog from &lt;a href=&quot;http://octopress.org/&quot;&gt;Octopress&lt;/a&gt; to vanilla &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;. I had initially enjoyed Octopress because it seemed to get me up and running in a short amount of time. It also included a pretty nice default theme along with some tools to use. However, the project seems to have been on a bit of a hiatus, and I think that it would be better in the long term if I just start to use Jekyll itself. While I lose some of the included tools in the Octopress rake tasks, I can probably re-write some of them myself now that I’m more comfortable with Jekyll.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I did the following items while migrating, which maybe someone will find useful.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3 id=&quot;syntax-highlighting&quot;&gt;Syntax highlighting&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rouge.jneen.net/&quot;&gt;Rouge&lt;/a&gt; is now the default syntax highlighter with Jekyll 3.0. After converting to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://liquidmarkup.org/&quot;&gt;Liquid&lt;/a&gt; tags and running jekyll serve, I got the following error:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Liquid Exception: undefined method `t&#39; for nil:NilClass in /Users/blah/blah/YYYY-MM-DD-some-post.markdown/#excerpt &lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;p&gt;Turns out that I couldn’t have syntax highlighting for the whole post. I didn’t dive too deep into it, but my simple fix was to add a first paragraph to the post so that there would be an excerpt available.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3 id=&quot;theme&quot;&gt;Theme&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;I used the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/poole/lanyon&quot;&gt;Lanyon&lt;/a&gt; theme. At the time that I did it, I had to manually apply &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/poole/lanyon/pull/149&quot;&gt;this pull request&lt;/a&gt; to get it working with Jekyll 3.0.&lt;/p&gt; </content> </entry> <entry> <title>The Baby Is Killing Me</title> <link href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/the-baby-is-killing-me/"/> <updated>2015-08-22T22:20:28-07:00</updated> <id>http://www.goingthewongway.com/the-baby-is-killing-me</id> <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We have been trying to keep 1 bottle feeding for the baby each day, but lately it’s been disastrous. Both of these statements feel about right, but they’re different so I don’t understand how they can both be true:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;The baby is sucking the life out of me&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;The baby is killing me by beating me down emotionally&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.gtww.net/2015/08_San_Diego/19e9/sd-1_883ce98.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; </content> </entry> <entry> <title>San Diego - The Bear's First Trip</title> <link href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/san-diego-the-bears-first-trip/"/> <updated>2015-08-16T22:27:47-07:00</updated> <id>http://www.goingthewongway.com/san-diego-the-bears-first-trip</id> <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So we took our first trip with The Bear, and we didn’t get out of the house any of the days until after 12 noon.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;galleria&quot;&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://img.gtww.net/2015/08_San_Diego/19e9/sd-2_28645f2.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-title=&quot;&quot; data-description=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://img.gtww.net/2015/08_San_Diego/19e9/Thumbs/sd-2_0d87.jpg&quot; height=&quot;40&quot; width=&quot;27&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://img.gtww.net/2015/08_San_Diego/19e9/sd-3_7496fb3.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-title=&quot;&quot; data-description=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://img.gtww.net/2015/08_San_Diego/19e9/Thumbs/sd-3_c282.jpg&quot; height=&quot;40&quot; width=&quot;60&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://img.gtww.net/2015/08_San_Diego/19e9/sd-4_158fcf5.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-title=&quot;&quot; data-description=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://img.gtww.net/2015/08_San_Diego/19e9/Thumbs/sd-4_e348.jpg&quot; height=&quot;40&quot; width=&quot;51&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://img.gtww.net/2015/08_San_Diego/19e9/sd-5_6fbae1e.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-title=&quot;&quot; data-description=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://img.gtww.net/2015/08_San_Diego/19e9/Thumbs/sd-5_55a7.jpg&quot; height=&quot;40&quot; width=&quot;60&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://img.gtww.net/2015/08_San_Diego/19e9/sd-6_f1fad48.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img data-title=&quot;&quot; data-description=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://img.gtww.net/2015/08_San_Diego/19e9/Thumbs/sd-6_e80f.jpg&quot; height=&quot;40&quot; width=&quot;27&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt; </content> </entry> <entry> <title>The Grass Is Greener (Even Though It Probably Shouldn't Be)</title> <link href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/the-grass-is-greener-even-though-it-probably-shouldnt-be/"/> <updated>2015-07-25T21:47:29-07:00</updated> <id>http://www.goingthewongway.com/the-grass-is-greener-even-though-it-probably-shouldnt-be</id> <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I live in California. It’s a state with plenty of fantastic attributes, but it has its drawbacks. There are the earthquakes. It’s really crowded. Housing is unpleasantly expensive. And we get droughts. In fact we’ve going through one for the past few years. At this point, there are starting to be more fines and publicity about what we should do to help.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;My neighbor is not really having any part of it. He waters his lawn at least 8 times each week (from what I can tell). I know because I’m up early in the morning feeding the baby so I hear both his first and his second watering (which he does at least 4 times each week). He’s also out there watering with a hose in the twilight hours sometimes, just to get those spots that the sprinklers might have missed. As you’d imagine, his lawn is lush and green. It’s nice, it really is. He mows it on average twice a week. He loves his lawn!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;We both redid our lawns at the same time a couple of years ago. We originally got the same grass, but after a year or so, he got too fed up with it because it would get brown spots. He didn’t like that. So he killed it and redid it again with different grass. Like I said, he loves his lawn.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Now usually this wouldn’t be a big deal. Except for that whole drought that we’re going through. So while everyone else might be trying to save water, my neighbor has a nice green lawn. To me, it seems pretty wasteful, and I wonder how much water he uses (I’m guessing a lot). Overall it doesn’t make sense for him to do it. It’s more expensive for him, it’s bad for Californians, and it’s not even par for the rest of the neighborhood (nowadays anyway).&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;So why does he do it? It’s his American dream. It’s where he places his hope, and it’s much more important to him than any of this other stuff. I feel bad for him because it seems like such an ephemeral hope. I really think that there could be more. I sure hope there is anyway!&lt;/p&gt; </content> </entry> <entry> <title>Getting Out</title> <link href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/getting-out/"/> <updated>2015-07-11T16:06:22-07:00</updated> <id>http://www.goingthewongway.com/getting-out</id> <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We’re getting out of the house more now that the little girl has gotten her vaccinations, and it almost feels like we’re normal people again!&lt;/p&gt; </content> </entry> </feed>