<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Christian | Going The Wong Way]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/categories/christian/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-02-11T21:54:39-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.goingthewongway.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Derek Wong]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Does God Clean Carpets?]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/does-god-clean-carpets/"/>
    <updated>2008-12-17T00:34:17-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.goingthewongway.com/does-god-clean-carpets</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When I'm driving around, I definitely notice when someone has Christian paraphernalia on their vehicle.  This can range anywhere from a fish emblem to the more clever slogans to mysterious symbols that are a little more difficult to deduce.  While I probably like seeing their proclamations of faith more than <a href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/2007/01/11/sell-your-porsche/">other things</a>, it can still lead to pretty interesting results.</p>

<p>A little while back I saw a van in and around Los Angeles, CA with the slogan: <strong><em>God's way is the best way</em></strong></p>

<p>The van was for a company that cleaned carpets named Best Way Carpet Clean.  In addition to the above slogan, they also had some fish stickers on their van.  Oh and there was a website listed on the van, but it seemed to be out of commission when I tried to access it.</p>

<p>In any case, what is the real motivation for them to put that on their van?  Seems to me that it is either because they hope:</p>

<ol>
<li><p>It will get them business because people are Christian and they'll trust another Christian</p></li>
<li><p>Non-Christians will think that Christians are more trustworthy so they'll be hired</p></li>
</ol>


<p>Whatever the reason, it seems to me that unless they made a special deal with God to miraculously clean carpets for them, it doesn't have too much of a place in that environment.  Not on their work van.  As it is, it just seems like a ploy to get more business and hence make more money.</p>

<p>Lesson is: be a Christian anywhere (even <a href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/2008/10/29/christian-rap/">as a rapper</a>), but don't do it out of incorrect motives.  Even if we can't figure it out, someone already knows when you have false intentions (where that someone is God).</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Christian Rap]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/christian-rap/"/>
    <updated>2008-10-29T01:30:39-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.goingthewongway.com/christian-rap</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Music is a wonderful thing.  Throughout the ages, it has been created and enjoyed by man.  It has ranged from the beat of the drum to the clang of the cymbal to the strings of the violin.</p>

<p>In and of itself, music is innocuous.  It is the words, lyrics, and association that we attach to these series of notes that give them their meaning.  That brings me to the point where I wonder at the derision of specific genres of music.  While I'm not a fan of every type of music (hardcore rock comes to mind), I do wonder sometimes at the motivation that people have for judgment.</p>

<p>Over the years, I've often heard both Christians and non-Christians deride so-called Christian rap (aka Gospel Rap, Holy Hip Hop, and so on and so on).  Basically it's music that identifies itself as hip hop with lyrics that could in someway be identified as Christian.  It seems that people mock it because they think that the combination of a culture of sex, drugs, and money that is often associated with the hip hop culture cannot be combined with what they perceive as stodgy, conservative Christianity.  Since they cannot go hand in hand, it's worthy of derision.</p>

<p>And yet I can pretty readily admit that I listen to and enjoy some of the music in this genre.  While I'm most definitely a fan of a wide variety of music (classic pop, r&b;, show tunes, alternative, trance, and more), some of my favorite artists might very well be clumped into this group.</p>

<p>Why I enjoy Christian rap:</p>

<ol>
<li><p><strong>Like-mindedness</strong> - While a lot of the groups and artists that I listen to don't constantly mention the name of Jesus Christ, I enjoy listening to them because I know that we come from the same place.  We're more alike than different because we are more fundamentally similar than to someone who does not share the faith.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Lyrics</strong> - Hardly anybody on the radio even has interesting lyrics.  It's the same old game of sex, money, and women.  Soulja boy?  Hardly stimulating.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Creativity</strong> - So granted, I don't listen to a lot of underground secular rappers.  But in my experience it seems that Christian groups that I listen to are much more wiling to try new things than the factory-pressed tracks heard on the radio.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Keeping It Real</strong> - This might seem extremely strange in a genre that many people think of as utterly fake, but I think that they're being more real when they create their works.  They're using their entire being, from their background in the 'hood all of the way to their conversion because of Christ.  They're not trying to hide these things, and I can respect that.</p></li>
</ol>


<p>So I don't enjoy ever single Christian rapper that I listen to.  Far from it.  But the same is true across the board for all musical genres.  Personally I enjoy those Christian rappers that like to talk about life, just like how I like to talk about life here on this blog.  But that is my own taste.</p>

<p>Even though it's been popular in society to mock the Jesus that I believe in (Jesus is my homeboy anyone?), I won't be party to it.  I rather wonder why people act that way.  Is it because (in the case of Christians) they're insecure about being so in-your-face about the faith?  Or perhaps it's because (in the case of non-Christians) they haven't experienced the same change?</p>

<p>Whatever it is, I might not ever know.</p>

<p>If you want to check out some free songs:
<a href="http://www.sphereofhiphop.com/mp3/index.php?option=com_content&amp;task=view&amp;id=13&amp;Itemid=30">List of free (and legal) Christian hip hop mp3s</a></p>

<p>Some of my favorites are:</p>

<ul>
<li><p>4th Avenue Jones (which have disbanded)</p></li>
<li><p>L.A. Symphony</p></li>
<li><p>Pigeon John (formerly of L.A. Symphony)</p></li>
<li><p>Grits</p></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Indebted]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/indebted/"/>
    <updated>2008-08-20T01:14:56-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.goingthewongway.com/indebted</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In today's world, there is a high priority placed on independence and individuality.  I know that I value this in myself and in others.</p>

<p>While some think that fellowship and community are important, it seems to me that there is a distinctly positive association with being able to think and act of one's own accord.  In the workplace, this is obviously true because any employer would want someone who can figure out what's wrong and solve something on their own without their manager's every guiding instruction.  But even outside of the workplace people like to see people who will help without being asked, not have to be told what to do every step of the way, and can come up with new ideas on their own.</p>

<p>Perhaps in this Randian society where man is elevated to the heroic nature that he is, we have gone even further such that our value system has become more sharply focused.  That is, instead of praising society, we praise the individual.</p>

<p>As a Christian, though, I shouldn't have such a high regard for the things that each of us can do on our own.  I should feel indebted.</p>

<p>Christianity, at its roots, holds the message that we have something that we have done zero work for.  The work that Jesus Christ did on the cross has made my sin null and void.  And that is a wonderful thing!  So while I can still appreciate independence in action, I need to always remember that ultimately I cannot hold it against others when they do not.  For what do I hold over them?  Nothing.  I should forgive my debts, for I am forgiven mine.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Unnecessary Incentive]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/unnecessary-incentive/"/>
    <updated>2007-04-01T18:25:42-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.goingthewongway.com/unnecessary-incentive</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Now passing judgment on people is not always good as we all know.  Of course people nowadays want there to be no judgments whatsoever.  And let's be honest, that doesn't really make any sense at all.  It makes about as much sense as getting rid of the court system, doesn't it?</p>

<p>Well I saw something today, and it is a case that definitely makes me think about some judgment passing.</p>

<p>Now far be it from me to know if someone actually understands what it means to be a Christian.  But I have to wonder about it when I see a sign on the street that proclaims that they should come to church in order to win a car.  They direct you to their website where they have <a href="http://www.ineedarevolution.com/easter/">a page dedicated to their contest</a>.</p>

<p>To me, that seems outlandish where they feel that they have a need to offer people physical prizes in order to attract them to come to their church.  Some out there will say that it's a good thing to get people into church no matter how they got there.  But is that really the right attitude?</p>

<p>Seems ridiculous to me, and I hope that this is not a growing trend.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Superbowl]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/superbowl/"/>
    <updated>2007-02-04T23:16:10-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.goingthewongway.com/superbowl</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So I'm sure that there are many entries out in the blog world about the exciting moments from the Superbowl, funny commercials, and numerous other topics.  <strong>This one is more important.</strong></p>

<p>Let me tell you, what stood out to me when I was watching the coverage and heard the stories about everything, was the life of Tony Dungy.</p>

<p>If you are unaware of who this is, he is the head coach of the Indianapolis Colts (the winning team of the Superbowl).  As I was hearing his story and reminded of the fact that this was the man who lost his 18-year old soon all too recently, I could not help but feel that this man had to be living differently.  His players and peers talked about how much they respected him, how he did not cuss (where the only time that he did was when he said that he was going to be on the "Best Damn Sports Show"), and numerous other character traits.  So I looked him up to see if he was a Christian.  And here are some of the things that I found: <a href="http://www.chattanoogan.com/articles/article_63714.asp">link 1</a> <a href="http://sports.espn.go.com/nfl/feature/featureVideo?page=amazinggrace">link 2</a> and many others.</p>

<p>Here is a man who is unafraid to live differently, who affects the lives of those around him even in a sub-culture of extreme opulence and outrageous antics.  He is a man who strives to be the best, is currently there, but does not let that stand in the way of who he really is.  Whether on top or on bottom, he is someone who seems to me has got it straight.  And I like that.</p>

<p>If I had known about this before, I would have cheered a little harder for the Colts (not that I was cheering for the Bears anyways).  Nevertheless my hats off to a man can do what seems to be so difficult in the world today: he brings his Christian beliefs into his life simply be being who he is.  He makes people <em>ask</em> why he is the way that he is.  He fights the good fight seemingly with his head squarely on his shoulders and his feet squarely on the Rock.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
