<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: nerd | Going The Wong Way]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/categories/nerd/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-05-23T22:15:19-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.goingthewongway.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Derek Wong]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Paying For Software]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/paying-for-software/"/>
    <updated>2011-06-16T01:14:37-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.goingthewongway.com/paying-for-software</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I am a big fan of <a href="http://www.gnu.org/philosophy/free-sw.html">free software</a> so it is no surprise that I use and advocate it when I can.  I would not consider myself <a href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/10/fanaticism/">fanatical</a> about it (i.e., I will and do use non-free software).  However, in my experience and observation I have noticed how difficult it is for people to pay for software.  How else can you explain how we can pay hundreds to thousands of dollars for a computer only to refuse to pay $20 for a particular desired application?</p>

<p>It seems that people are confused about developers, especially those that create free software.  Maybe they do not think that the developers are entitled to compensation because they are releasing free software.  I guess that in part it is due to the difference between the definitions of free (as in zero cost) and free (as in liberty).  Software developers are (surprise!) real people that need to make a living as well.  In a world that contains both free (as in zero cost) and free (as in liberty) software, people need to understand both in order for them to see where the software developer is coming from.  So perhaps we can all remember that paying for software should be seen just like we should view all other purchases - if it satisfies our requirements for purchasing then we should go ahead and do that.</p>

<p>All of these words when this abbreviated comic (originally <a href="http://theoatmeal.com/blog/apps">here</a>) says it perhaps even better:</p>

<p><img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/theoatmeal-img/comics/apps/3.png" alt="Buying an expensive iPhone" /><img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/theoatmeal-img/comics/apps/5.png" alt="Cannot buy paid app" /></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Public Restrooms Are Scary]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/public-restrooms-are-scary/"/>
    <updated>2009-11-05T12:16:24-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.goingthewongway.com/public-restrooms-are-scary</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<pre><code class="python"># use_public_toilet.py
#
# Algorithm for using a public toilet.  Success will vary based on the
# toilet/situation (obviously).  However, this seems to be a generally safe
# way to approach using a toilet.
#
# Handles both male and female needs as well as exceptional cases such as
# no available toilet, getting dirty, and entering the wrong gender's
# bathroom.
#
# Algorithm is roughly:
# 1) Enter bathroom
# 2) Find suitable toilet
# 3) Protect yourself if it's a stall toilet that you sit on
# 4) Do your business
# 5) Finish up

import common_sense

# Sometimes even nature's calling cannot overrule common sense
# Including when you walk into the wrong bathroom
if (bathroom.is_disgusting or bathroom.is_dangerous
    or bathroom.gender != you.gender):
    you.hold('your waste')
    return # (i.e., get out of there!)    

my_toilet = None
# Only male urinaters get to use the urinals, at least in the common case
# (Abnormal cases are unhandled here)
if you.need() == 'urinate' and you.gender == 'male':
    for urinal in bathroom.urinals:
        if not urinal.empty:
            continue
        my_toilet = urinal    

# If you are not a male urinating or there is no urinal available
if my_toilet is None:
    # Time to look for the stall
    for stall in bathroom.stalls:
        # Use an empty toilet that can also be initialized to a clean state
        if not stall.empty or (not toilet.clean and not toilet.works):
            continue
        you.enter('Stall %s' % stall)
        my_toilet = stall
        break
    else:
        # You could not find a suitable stall to use
        return

    you.wipe('toilet seat')
    you.put('toilet seat cover')
    while not toilet.seat_covered():
        you.put('toilet paper')

# Finally the time has come to get down to business
try:
    you.sit()
    you.do_your_business()
except TouchDirtyException:   # Don't touch the toilet!
    you.cry()


you.flush(my_toilet)
you.wash_hands()
you.leave()
if you.satisfied:             # Be happy, you're done
    you.smile()
</code></pre>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Understanding Domains]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/understanding-domains/"/>
    <updated>2009-09-03T01:12:24-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.goingthewongway.com/understanding-domains</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If I could have your attention, I would rather like to quickly rant about something that I see all of the time.</p>

<ol>
<li>People pay for their own domain name</li>
<li>Those same people want to get e-mail</li>
<li>Those people proceed to register an e-mail address with some free webmail (e.g., Yahoo!, Google, etc)</li>
</ol>


<p>Why does require a rant?  Because they paid for their own domain!  Instead of having to register SomeOrganizationSomeGroup@gmail.com, they could very well just decide that they want to get <a href="&#x6d;&#x61;&#105;&#x6c;&#x74;&#111;&#58;&#x53;&#111;&#109;&#101;&#71;&#x72;&#x6f;&#x75;&#x70;&#64;&#84;&#x68;&#x65;&#105;&#114;&#68;&#x6f;&#x6d;&#x61;&#105;&#110;&#46;&#99;&#111;&#x6d;&#x2e;">&#83;&#111;&#109;&#x65;&#71;&#114;&#x6f;&#x75;&#112;&#x40;&#84;&#x68;&#101;&#x69;&#x72;&#68;&#111;&#109;&#x61;&#105;&#x6e;&#46;&#x63;&#111;&#109;&#46;</a>  Doesn&rsquo;t that seem more appealing?  Isn&rsquo;t that more professional and more enjoyable?  Yes, yes I think that we can all agree to that.</p>

<p>The only argument that I can think of is that people want to be able to use the webmail clients to access their e-mail.  I hear ya.  But maybe more importantly, Google hears ya.  I don&rsquo;t want to be a Google salesman, but their <a href="http://www.google.com/apps/intl/en/group/index.html">standard edition of Google Apps</a> is pretty free.  And that will pretty much take care of you.</p>

<p>Together, we can combat annoying-to-remember e-mail addresses.  We can do it!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tough To Say Whether It's Even Decent]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/tough-to-say-whether-its-even-decent/"/>
    <updated>2009-06-18T01:20:33-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.goingthewongway.com/tough-to-say-whether-its-even-decent</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have been working on a budgeting application called <a href="http://budse.sourceforge.net/">Budse</a> (actually for quite some time now).  It&rsquo;s a straight forward application that allows you to create a set of accounts that have rules assigned to them, which dictate how to split up whole account deposits (e.g., a paycheck).  I originally had the idea because I wanted to start budgeting using the <a href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/199/is-the-40-30-20-10-rule-too-ideal/">40-30-20-10 rule</a>.  But then I realized that I wanted to use the idea but customize it a little bit more for my needs.</p>

<p>But enough about the details.  On to my point.</p>

<p>So I am working on Budse by myself.  I started the project, and it has been a one-man show the whole time.  As an individual developer working on an open source project, sometimes I dream.  I start to think big about people actually using it.  Big dreams, I know.  Haha currently I doubt it if anyone aside from me uses it.  When I was coding and especially when I was deciding on how to license it, I thought that since it fulfilled my need it would be useful to other people as well.  Maybe that&rsquo;s not true.  Maybe it is.  It remains to be seen.</p>

<p>It is so easy to dream of becoming great.  But maybe dreaming big isn&rsquo;t such a bad thing.  Maybe if I lost the ability to dream big, I would lose a little bit of who I am.  So while I am currently unsatisfied with its use, I am definitely going to press forward!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Go, Go, Stop!]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/go-go-stop/"/>
    <updated>2009-03-20T01:06:26-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.goingthewongway.com/go-go-stop</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I often like to think about things that I take for granted.  It makes me more appreciative of what I have, and I don&rsquo;t think that&rsquo;s a bad thing at all.  A while back, I was thinking about how great the yellow light is.  For me, more often than not it&rsquo;s a sign that says, &ldquo;figure out if you can make this light!&rdquo;  Sometimes this is a resounding yes, and sometimes it&rsquo;s a resounding no.  Sometimes it&rsquo;s even &ldquo;you better get going pronto!&rdquo;  Can you imagine, though, what it would be like without yellow lights?  Drivers would be moseying along thinking that they&rsquo;re good to go, when all of a sudden they need to slam on their brakes.  Accidents would abound because brakes cannot stop you instantly.</p>

<p>Recently, I even got to experience a similar kind of fun.  Many of the lights along a street that I commute on were out.  So as expected all of the cars treated each malfunctioning light as an all-way stop intersection.  And that wrecked havoc on my commute.  Boy am I glad for signals!</p>

<p>Oddly enough, this reminded me of a problem that I am dealing with at work.  The problem is that I am trying to make a single database access for every single object that I want to create.  That would be analogous to a stop sign which lets everyone through one at a time.  Ideally I am trying to code things that will allow for multiple objects with a single database connection.  This would be with the lights that let multiple cars through.  I do enjoy finding out how <a href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/2007/08/21/how-good-programming-practices-help-in-real-life/">good software practices relate to life</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
