<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Random | Going The Wong Way]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/categories/random/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-02-12T21:59:32-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.goingthewongway.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Derek Wong]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[DIY Camera Strap]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/diy-camera-strap/"/>
    <updated>2011-09-30T07:05:32-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.goingthewongway.com/diy-camera-strap</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I love making things instead of buying them. First I made a <a href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/643/diy-camera-bag/">stealthy camera bag</a>.  And here I am making a better strap for my DSLR.  I was inspired by looking around the Instructables website at other people's camera straps.  In particular, I was fond of the variants of the highly regarded <a href="http://amzn.to/NoFYby">R-Strap by Black Rapid</a>.</p>

<div class="galleria">
<a href="http://img.gtww.net/2011/06_Camera_Strap/2a6c/DIY_camera_strap-1_c973494.jpg"><img data-title="Supplies" data-description="Here are the supplies that I initially used. Unfortunately I started working on it before remembering to take a picture!" src="http://img.gtww.net/2011/06_Camera_Strap/2a6c/Thumbs/DIY_camera_strap-1_388a.jpg"/></a>
<a href="http://img.gtww.net/2011/06_Camera_Strap/2a6c/DIY_camera_strap-2_8d40b96.jpg"><img data-title="" data-description="" src="http://img.gtww.net/2011/06_Camera_Strap/2a6c/Thumbs/DIY_camera_strap-2_7d31.jpg"/></a>
<a href="http://img.gtww.net/2011/06_Camera_Strap/2a6c/DIY_camera_strap-3_423bdd5.jpg"><img data-title="" data-description="" src="http://img.gtww.net/2011/06_Camera_Strap/2a6c/Thumbs/DIY_camera_strap-3_76a6.jpg"/></a>
<a href="http://img.gtww.net/2011/06_Camera_Strap/2a6c/DIY_camera_strap-4_5672ebc.jpg"><img data-title="Box Stitch" data-description="Box stitches can hold my rainbow sandals through all kinds of abuse.  I think that it will be sufficient here." src="http://img.gtww.net/2011/06_Camera_Strap/2a6c/Thumbs/DIY_camera_strap-4_04b0.jpg"/></a>
<a href="http://img.gtww.net/2011/06_Camera_Strap/2a6c/DIY_camera_strap-5_0496f8c.jpg"><img data-title="Prevent Fraying" data-description="Used the flame from a lighter to (carefully) melt the edge of the nylon strap.  This prevents fraying quite nicely." src="http://img.gtww.net/2011/06_Camera_Strap/2a6c/Thumbs/DIY_camera_strap-5_35f7.jpg"/></a>
<a href="http://img.gtww.net/2011/06_Camera_Strap/2a6c/DIY_camera_strap-6_01a5d9f.jpg"><img data-title="Cut Original Strap" data-description="My original strap is now cut!  I used the original strap because the nylon that connects the strap to the camera is exactly the correct size.  Additionally I know that it is solidly sewn and able to withstand the weight of the camera (since that's kind of what it does)." src="http://img.gtww.net/2011/06_Camera_Strap/2a6c/Thumbs/DIY_camera_strap-6_38dd.jpg"/></a>
<a href="http://img.gtww.net/2011/06_Camera_Strap/2a6c/DIY_camera_strap-7_47a6e3c.jpg"><img data-title="Grommet" data-description="Install grommet into original camera strap" src="http://img.gtww.net/2011/06_Camera_Strap/2a6c/Thumbs/DIY_camera_strap-7_50c7.jpg"/></a>
<a href="http://img.gtww.net/2011/06_Camera_Strap/2a6c/DIY_camera_strap-8_d562607.jpg"><img data-title="With Camera" data-description="Strap with camera attached to it" src="http://img.gtww.net/2011/06_Camera_Strap/2a6c/Thumbs/DIY_camera_strap-8_4f2a.jpg"/></a>
<a href="http://img.gtww.net/2011/06_Camera_Strap/2a6c/DIY_camera_strap-9_94aa585.jpg"><img data-title="Assembled" data-description="Here is the assembled harness.  I connect this to the grommet on the original camera strap and then I thread my shoulder strap through the nylon strap and the carabiner.  In actuality, I don't need both the nylon strap and the carabiner.  Originally I only had the nylon strap, but I found that it had too much friction with the shoulder strap.  So with both the nylon strap and the carabiner I get the benefit of less friction between the carabiner and the shoulder strap along with double safety in case either the nylon strap or the carabiner fails (neither of which seems likely to me)." src="http://img.gtww.net/2011/06_Camera_Strap/2a6c/Thumbs/DIY_camera_strap-9_4a57.jpg"/></a>
<a href="http://img.gtww.net/2011/06_Camera_Strap/2a6c/DIY_camera_strap-10_79b806d.jpg"><img data-title="Modeled" data-description="Here's a model to show you what it looks like in action.  As you can see, it is out of the way and not pulling down on the neck (in the bothersome way that the Canon strap does)." src="http://img.gtww.net/2011/06_Camera_Strap/2a6c/Thumbs/DIY_camera_strap-10_a307.jpg"/></a>
</div>


<h4>Steps</h4>

<ol>
<li>Sew nylon strap through swiveling hook with a box stitch</li>
<li>Attach locking carabiner to swiveling hook</li>
<li>Thread shoulder strap through both nylon strap and carabiner</li>
<li>Cut original Canon strap, leaving enough room on the thick portion for a grommet</li>
<li>Cut hole in thick portion, not too close to the edges</li>
<li>Insert and attach grommet</li>
<li>Attach skinny nylon strap of the original Canon strap to the camera</li>
<li>Attach grommet on thick portion of original Canon strap to the swiveling hook</li>
</ol>


<h4>Parts</h4>

<ul>
<li>Grommet kit ($7, Michael's)</li>
<li>Included Canon strap (free or less than $10, eBay)</li>
<li>Swiveling hook ($4, Home Depot)</li>
<li><a href="http://amzn.to/Rz7V35">Locking carabiner</a> ($5, Amazon)</li>
<li>Nylon strap (free, cut from an old messenger bag)</li>
<li>Thread (negligible, already had)</li>
<li>Shoulder strap (free, already had)</li>
</ul>


<h4>Conclusion</h4>

<p>I enjoyed making this, especially when compared to the ~$60 R-Strap.  It saved me some money.  (Then again, that small amount of money saved hardly gets me very far in terms of purchasing new lenses!)</p>

<p>My main issues with the commercial R-Strap is its price and its attachment to the tripod mount.  I don't particularly trust screws to hold my camera, especially since it swings and hangs there.  Additionally, it is quite difficult to put a camera on a tripod with something else attached to its tripod mount!  This strap attaches to one of the metal tabs that is normally used for holding up the camera.  It's integral to the camera body, and I trust that it won't break.  If it does break, then it would drop just as it would have if I were only using the original Canon strap.  In any case it is a pretty secure setup, and I will be using this for the time being.</p>

<p>A lot of my inspiration is from the <a href="http://www.goingthewongway.comhttp://www.instructables.com/id/Safer-DIY-R-Strap/">Safer DIY R-Strap</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Being Thankful For Monetary Gifts]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/being-thankful-for-monetary-gifts/"/>
    <updated>2010-09-17T01:18:22-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.goingthewongway.com/being-thankful-for-monetary-gifts</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Growing up (maybe just because it was growing up in the United States of America), I have become accustomed to getting gifts.  There are presents for birthdays, graduations, Christmas, and other events that society deems worthy.  There are all kinds of gifts, too.  There are handmade gifts, clothes, toys, service coupons (e.g., breakfast in bed), simple cards, gift cards, and even the classic dollar bill(s).</p>

<p>As a child I used to enjoy getting money as much (and probably more than) any other type of gift.  It is of the utmost in practicality since it can be used for anything that the receiver desires.  It is also much easier on the giver since it removes all of the effort involved in finding and purchasing a gift.</p>

<p>But I think, as a receiver of gifts, therein lies the reason why my embrace of money has declined as I have aged.  There is no work on the part of the giver.  Actually I should take that back because they do have to work at a job in order to actually receive that money.  But a giver of money does <strong>not</strong> need to wonder about the recipient's desires or tastes.  They do not need to go out searching for an appropriate gift that will delight.  I appreciate the work that is involved in all of that.  (Even if, sometimes, the gift turns out to be awful.  If that is the case, I indeed would probably prefer money, but I can still try to appreciate the work and attempt that the giver made.)</p>

<p>Which leads me to my method of dealing with monetary gifts.  I can happily receive such a gift, but I also try my best to set aside that money and use it on something pleasant.  In that way, I can tangibly interact with the gift that has been given to me.  I find that it makes me much more thankful to have, say, a room fan rather than $50 in my pocket that will be spent over time on miscellaneous soon-forgotten expenses (e.g., parking meter).  The fan can cool me on a summer night.  The $50?  Not nearly as well.</p>

<p>In any case, can it really hurt any of us to be more thankful people?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Noticing Wedding Gifts]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/noticing-wedding-gifts/"/>
    <updated>2010-07-21T01:43:14-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.goingthewongway.com/noticing-wedding-gifts</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I often figure that when I am in a large crowd, I will be much less noticed than when I am alone.  This often turns out to be true, and I often enjoy blending in with the crowd.  It provides a measure of anonymity that is sometimes desirable.</p>

<p>Weddings can be small or large affairs where each individual guest is merely a single person in a larger group.  So it can stand to reason that each guest will think that they do not stand out too much.</p>

<p>While we (my wife and I) made a conscious effort to be thankful for everything that was given to us, I have an insider's tip for everyone that has not gone through a wedding yet: the bride and groom notice a lot more than you think.  That means that your thoughtful, generous, cheap, or even missing gifts are noticed.  This directly correlates with how close to the married couple you are.  Do not be fooled into thinking that of 10's, 100's, or even 1000's of gifts yours will not be noticed.  While the day of the wedding might be a blur, the aftermath of finding out what people decided to gift you with is a much longer process that allows for more consideration.</p>

<p>The purpose of weddings is <strong>definitely</strong> not gifts, but I figured that this tip might be useful to a lot of people who had not discovered it for themselves already.  Either that, or we are the only ones, and we might have noticed you (for good or for bad).  Remember that sometimes it's the thought that counts and sometimes the thought only gets you so much.  And then you have to at least give a well thought out card!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Take It Easy, Old Fella]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/take-it-easy-old-fella/"/>
    <updated>2010-03-26T01:15:03-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.goingthewongway.com/take-it-easy-old-fella</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As the weather warms up, I start to see more people out and about getting their exercise on.  That is, they're either getting out of the stuffy gym for some sunshine or they are actually realizing that it is nice to be outside instead of sitting on the couch.  Whatever their reason, it is good to see them out there.</p>

<p><strong>Unless of course they are old.</strong>  Yeah, that is probably an ageist statement no matter how you slice it.</p>

<p>Anyways, my whole point is that an old person should not be running in 85° F heat with either a plastic suit or a sweatshirt/sweatpants on.  There are some things that are good and important (like exercise).  There is also a fair amount of wisdom in knowing when to take it 100% and when to err on the safe side.  A young guy trying to sweat out some water to make weight for high school wrestling can take the plastic suit a little better than an older gentleman in his 60s who is just trying to slim down for the ladies at the retirement home.</p>

<p>So remember, friends don't let friends let their grandparents go on a crash diet to get ready for cage fighting.  What, cage fighting?  Yeah that definitely seems like the only reasonable place for anyone over the age of 22 (i.e., post-collegiate wrestling) to wear a plastic suit.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Water War (Card Game)]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/water-war-card-game/"/>
    <updated>2010-02-15T00:20:01-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.goingthewongway.com/water-war-card-game</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Inspired by <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/War_%28card_game%29">war</a>, here is a fun little game that was concocted by yours truly.  In keeping with finding out the <a href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/773/the-origin-of-things/">origin of things</a>, this took place at the winter retreat of the Hi Koi fellowship in December 2007.  Anyways, the game adds the mindlessness of war with punishments and randomness that will amuse you to no end.  It is good clean fun!  And it happens to be good for you!</p>

<p><strong>Equipment</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>At least 1 deck of cards</li>
<li>2+ players</li>
<li>1 cup for each player</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Gameplay</strong>
Deal all of the cards to each player (as in war).  Players are not to look at their cards.  Play occurs in rounds ("battles") with each player revealing the top card in their pile.  The highest card (ace is high) is the winner.  All players with cards lower than the highest relinquish their card to the player with the highest card as well as drink an arbitrarily small amount of water (i.e., a sip).  If the 2 players have equally high cards, they are now to engage in a "war" with each player placing their top 3 cards facedown and revealing the 4th card.  This continues until one of the players engaged in the "war" has a higher card.  The loser of the war must relinquish all cards as well as drink the rest of the water in their cup.  Once a player has lost all of their cards, they are eliminated.  Each loser must drink the number of cups of water relative to their standing (i.e., the first person eliminated with 6 players has a standing of 6th and will then drink 6 cups of water).</p>

<p><strong>Alternate Versions:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Winner must drink the water</li>
<li>Use food instead of water</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
