<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Personal | Going The Wong Way]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/categories/personal/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-03-15T09:44:54-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.goingthewongway.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Derek Wong]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Self Branding]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/self-branding/"/>
    <updated>2011-06-02T01:37:57-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.goingthewongway.com/self-branding</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Farmers have used branding for a long time as a way to mark their property, namely their livestock.  They knew that if their livestock wandered off (as they invariably would) then they needed a way to make sure that they had a way to get their property back.  It was a wonderful idea for the farmers.  But what did the livestock think?  I am sure that the livestock were not huge fans of the process.  Having a hot metal brand pressed into their skin was probably not on their list of highlights from their lives.  But they didn&rsquo;t have a choice.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/179/applegeeks-coachgirls/">Apple stickers</a> on cars, Gucci emblems on purses (<a href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/70/even-worse-than-at-first-glance/">real or fake</a>), and perhaps even soccer jerseys with their large corporate sponsorship logos are all things that seem to follow this idea.  It&rsquo;s a strange idea really because we are paying companies so that we can advertise for them.  If I walked up to you and asked if you would pay me money in order to wear a necklace with my name on it you would think that I am crazy.  Is the idea that we would pay to display companies' logos that far off from this example?</p>

<p>Nowadays people have a choice.  And I am always surprised when people  choose self-branding.  Instead of viewing it as branding, though, they want to display an affiliation, love the cachet/exclusivity, or perhaps just do it because  others do it also.</p>

<p>In truth, we all do it to some degree.  We buy T-shirts, computers, and cars that all have logos on them.  So I would doubt very much if anyone is exempt.  But thinking about it sure does make one think.  And it sure does give me a different perspective of &ldquo;brand&rdquo; names.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[2011 Los Angeles 13.1 Race Report]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/2011-los-angeles-13-1-race-report/"/>
    <updated>2011-01-16T14:37:32-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.goingthewongway.com/2011-los-angeles-13-1-race-report</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Running has just become a part of my life. I hear others talk about how they think that it&rsquo;s sheer craziness, and I know that I would have agreed at times in my life with that sentiment. But since my mind was changed around 7 years ago I have gone from <a href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/389/half-marathon/">my first half</a> to <a href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/596/finishing-my-first-marathon/">a full</a> and even starting to mix in a fair share of <a href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/631/barefoot-running/">barefoot running</a>. With this in mind I decided to do another half marathon with some friends from church.</p>

<p>This half marathon stands apart from the other races that I did because I believe that I did nearly all of my training for it barefoot. There might have been a couple of runs that I ran shod, but I don&rsquo;t particularly remember them even when I ran in Boston, MA in November or during the cold temperatures here in Los Angeles, CA (~36 degrees Fahrenheit at night). In any case I was fairly set on trying to do this barefoot, but I hurt my heel on my very last tapered run 2 days before the race! I was trying to run on the street more since it was going to be a street race, but it did not go well. I am sure that there are errors in my form, and these will need to be addressed in the future. This started to give me some idea to what my problems were going to be for the race. The pain in my heel was slight, but I knew from past experience that any slight pain will be hugely magnified over the course of many miles. This made me start to doubt whether I would be able to finish the race barefoot.</p>

<p>The morning of the race went well. We all slept well and got up ready to go. I brought my shoes along just in case the conditions were unbearable, but I decided to leave them in the car when we finally got there. At the starting line I went up to the 8-9 minute/mile corral just before they started the race. The first mile along the boardwalk was grand since it was concrete, and I have plenty of concrete sidewalk experience. However near the first mile marker the course turned onto Venice Blvd. That first portion went decently even if there were some rough spots. Just to give you an idea from <a href="http://therunningbarefoot.com/?p=625s">Ken Bob&rsquo;s Terrain Guide</a>, I had trained mostly on grades near 6 or 7 while the actual surface of those Santa Monica streets oftentimes warranted a 3 or 4.</p>

<p>In any case I continued on my merry way, doing okay until between miles 8 and 9. It was at that point that I was starting to feel the pain quite a bit, and it was affecting me a lot. I refused to stop or walk, but I was not doing well. Instead of passing people, I was starting to get passed. I won&rsquo;t lie, it was rough going. The surface seemed to have gotten worse on the way back, but it could have just been that I was more sensitive after having run all of those other miles.</p>

<p>Those last 5 miles were torturous. I knew that I had to make it, and I knew that I could not stop. I reasoned with myself that stopping to walk just meant more time on my feet, and that was the last thing that I wanted at that point. I approached the end, thankfully, and I&rsquo;m pretty sure that I picked it up in the last half of a mile as the finish line neared simply based on the fact that I was soon going to be able to get off of my feet. For the next 2 hours I was either sitting with my feet off of the pavement or hobbling uncomfortably because my feet were too tender to walk very far.</p>

<p>I did get to meet a nice older fellow who had run the race barefoot. He looked pretty comfortable as he was walking around afterward, but we chatted and he shook my hand in congratulating me on my first barefoot half marathon. I&rsquo;m pretty sure that he thought that I was slightly foolish for only having run my longest barefoot run at ~10 miles prior to that race, though.</p>

<p>I don&rsquo;t have too many pictures because honestly I only had 2 things on my mind. My right and my left feet. But the short story is:</p>

<ul>
<li>I did not train far enough in my distances.</li>
<li>I did not train on the correct surfaces.</li>
<li>I will be hobbling for a little while.</li>
<li><a href="http://results.active.com/pages/oneResult.jsp?pID=98847911&amp;rsID=105097&amp;pubID=3">I did it.</a></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wavering Importance]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/wavering-importance/"/>
    <updated>2010-06-28T01:45:11-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.goingthewongway.com/wavering-importance</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If it&rsquo;s true that the importance that things have wavers according to what else is happening then I guess it just goes to show that this blog didn&rsquo;t have a really high place in my heart.  While I have been making sure that it&rsquo;s still running and checking on it every now and then, I have not written a new post in quite awhile.  But now that I am sitting here in my very own house with this ring on my finger I guess that the blog is rising back up.</p>

<p>I sure am glad because I have not had a public place to air my thoughts.  And that means that either I have been keeping it in or even worse I have not been having any interesting thoughts.  I enjoy writing posts that act as a running commentary on interesting thoughts that I have rather than those of a personal nature, but I figured that I needed to break back into this whole blog thing with something easy.  And what is easier than spilling about what has already happened to you?</p>

<p>So that was my way of saying sorry for not writing, but I was busy buying a house and getting married!  But I&rsquo;m back!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Barefoot Running]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/barefoot-running/"/>
    <updated>2009-07-10T01:10:25-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.goingthewongway.com/barefoot-running</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>That title probably gets your attention.  As is common knowledge, we need shoes in order to run.  Running barefoot is impossible to comprehend.  Except&hellip;it&rsquo;s not.  There are so many reasons that I have found that compel me to run barefoot.  And I figured that now would be a good time to post them here.</p>

<p>I have been running barefoot for over 9 months now.  I started off running a few blocks, and I have progressed to now run a few miles a couple of times each week.  Yes, it will sometimes be briefly uncomfortable when I step on a pebble, but it is usually gone in the next step.  However for most people the thought of pain is enough to prevent them from ever trying to run barefoot.  On the other hand, just because I run on the street does not mean that everyone has to.  <img style="float:right;" width="240" title="Yep, they're mine" src="http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2554/3706453438_b247aaa513_m.jpg"/>
Running on sand or grass would definitely be more comfortable, but it&rsquo;s really not that bad running on the pavement (in my opinion).  I believe that running barefoot is better, and I want my behavior to be in accordance with my beliefs.</p>

<ul>
<li>I was <strong>not born</strong> with shoes.  (Of course I also wasn&rsquo;t born with clothes, but clothes don&rsquo;t injure me.  If they did, I wouldn&rsquo;t wear those either.)</li>
<li><strong>Injuries increase with the price</strong> of the shoes according to surveys from runners.</li>
<li>It&rsquo;s recommended (by pediatricians) that <strong>young children be allowed to walk around barefoot</strong> so that they can develop their feet.  There must be something there, right?</li>
<li>By the laws of <strong>physics</strong> the force of each step when running has to be translated and absorved somewhere.  Running sure isn&rsquo;t hurting your feet.  Where does that leave?  Perhaps the knees and hips?</li>
<li>Tough and hardened feet are much more <strong>useful</strong> than soft tender feet.  Soft feet are nice to the touch, but they can&rsquo;t nearly do what used feet can do.  If you had to run away from danger, you can&rsquo;t exactly stop to put on your shoes.</li>
<li>Without the artificial support of shoes, your feet need to balance and adapt.  That is, the <strong>muscles and tendons in your feet will get stronger</strong>.  It&rsquo;s similar to why it&rsquo;s excellent to do exercises without artificial support.  You need to balance while also performing the task at hand.  And that will make you stronger and strengthen the entire structure.</li>
<li>There sure are a lot of people from <strong>other countries</strong> that are awesome runners without the need for shoes.  Have you ever thought about that?  Not only are they awesome, but they have lower incidence of injury.  Just because I wasn&rsquo;t born in a culture like that does not mean that I cannot become like that!</li>
<li>I stand for <strong>freedom</strong>!.  I always have, I always will.  But it is a different kind of freedom that I feel when I&rsquo;m running barefoot.  It kind of makes me feel like a little kid, and I love that.</li>
<li>The arch is one of the strongest structures known to man.  We use it for bridges to hold up amazing amounts of weight.  Have you ever seen an arched bridge have something filling the entire arch?  No.  That&rsquo;s because the <strong>arch is strongest when there is nothing filling that gap</strong>.  Surprise, surprise guess where we have an arch.</li>
<li>One of the most important reason to consider running barefoot is that it makes you more <strong>conscious of your running form</strong>.  So while your form might suffer when you&rsquo;re running with shod feet, you won&rsquo;t modify your behavior because it doesn&rsquo;t manifest itself until years of running have beaten your body down.  However you will definitely notice the difference with bare feet.  You will not strike your heel.  You will land on the balls of your feet.  You will be careful of where you go.  You could learn how to run with better form from someone teaching you.  But that doesn&rsquo;t mean that you&rsquo;re necessarily going to change.  Pain is a much better way to modify your behavior than mere information.  It&rsquo;s a reminder every step that you need to run correctly.</li>
</ul>


<p>I run barefoot.  I enjoy it.</p>

<p>References:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.sportsci.org/jour/0103/mw.htm">SportSci &ndash; Running Barefoot</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/home/moslive/article-1170253/The-painful-truth-trainers-Are-expensive-running-shoes-waste-money.html">The Painful Truth About Trainers</a></li>
<li><a href="http://barefootrunner.org/">Barefoot Rick</a> &ndash; I enjoyed reading some of his articles and thoughts about running barefoot.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Maybe I'll Miss That Pit]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/maybe-ill-miss-that-pit/"/>
    <updated>2009-06-20T01:40:28-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.goingthewongway.com/maybe-ill-miss-that-pit</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After reading <a href="http://www.boundless.org/2005/articles/a0002060.cfm">The Long Journey From Obesity</a>, I started to realize that I was like the author before she became an obese person.  At times I look down on obese people because I think that it <strong>is</strong> possible for them to lose weight.  And while I still do think that it is true for them in a lot of cases, I can easily lose sight of the fact that being skinny is not the most important thing.</p>

<p>There are skinny gluttonous people and there are larger fit people.  Size is not of the utmost importance.  It would do me well to remember this.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
