<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Sports | Going The Wong Way]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/categories/sports/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-09-29T11:44:53-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.goingthewongway.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Derek Wong]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[2011 Los Angeles 13.1 Race Report]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/2011-los-angeles-13-1-race-report/"/>
    <updated>2011-01-16T14:37:32-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.goingthewongway.com/2011-los-angeles-13-1-race-report</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Running has just become a part of my life. I hear others talk about how they think that it's sheer craziness, and I know that I would have agreed at times in my life with that sentiment. But since my mind was changed around 7 years ago I have gone from <a href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/389/half-marathon/">my first half</a> to <a href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/596/finishing-my-first-marathon/">a full</a> and even starting to mix in a fair share of <a href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/631/barefoot-running/">barefoot running</a>. With this in mind I decided to do another half marathon with some friends from church.</p>

<p>This half marathon stands apart from the other races that I did because I believe that I did nearly all of my training for it barefoot. There might have been a couple of runs that I ran shod, but I don't particularly remember them even when I ran in Boston, MA in November or during the cold temperatures here in Los Angeles, CA (~36 degrees Fahrenheit at night). In any case I was fairly set on trying to do this barefoot, but I hurt my heel on my very last tapered run 2 days before the race! I was trying to run on the street more since it was going to be a street race, but it did not go well. I am sure that there are errors in my form, and these will need to be addressed in the future. This started to give me some idea to what my problems were going to be for the race. The pain in my heel was slight, but I knew from past experience that any slight pain will be hugely magnified over the course of many miles. This made me start to doubt whether I would be able to finish the race barefoot.</p>

<p>The morning of the race went well. We all slept well and got up ready to go. I brought my shoes along just in case the conditions were unbearable, but I decided to leave them in the car when we finally got there. At the starting line I went up to the 8-9 minute/mile corral just before they started the race. The first mile along the boardwalk was grand since it was concrete, and I have plenty of concrete sidewalk experience. However near the first mile marker the course turned onto Venice Blvd. That first portion went decently even if there were some rough spots. Just to give you an idea from <a href="http://therunningbarefoot.com/?p=625s">Ken Bob's Terrain Guide</a>, I had trained mostly on grades near 6 or 7 while the actual surface of those Santa Monica streets oftentimes warranted a 3 or 4.</p>

<p>In any case I continued on my merry way, doing okay until between miles 8 and 9. It was at that point that I was starting to feel the pain quite a bit, and it was affecting me a lot. I refused to stop or walk, but I was not doing well. Instead of passing people, I was starting to get passed. I won't lie, it was rough going. The surface seemed to have gotten worse on the way back, but it could have just been that I was more sensitive after having run all of those other miles.</p>

<p>Those last 5 miles were torturous. I knew that I had to make it, and I knew that I could not stop. I reasoned with myself that stopping to walk just meant more time on my feet, and that was the last thing that I wanted at that point. I approached the end, thankfully, and I'm pretty sure that I picked it up in the last half of a mile as the finish line neared simply based on the fact that I was soon going to be able to get off of my feet. For the next 2 hours I was either sitting with my feet off of the pavement or hobbling uncomfortably because my feet were too tender to walk very far.</p>

<p>I did get to meet a nice older fellow who had run the race barefoot. He looked pretty comfortable as he was walking around afterward, but we chatted and he shook my hand in congratulating me on my first barefoot half marathon. I'm pretty sure that he thought that I was slightly foolish for only having run my longest barefoot run at ~10 miles prior to that race, though.</p>

<p>I don't have too many pictures because honestly I only had 2 things on my mind. My right and my left feet. But the short story is:</p>

<ul>
<li>I did not train far enough in my distances.</li>
<li>I did not train on the correct surfaces.</li>
<li>I will be hobbling for a little while.</li>
<li><a href="http://results.active.com/pages/oneResult.jsp?pID=98847911&amp;rsID=105097&amp;pubID=3">I did it.</a></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bowling High]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/bowling-high/"/>
    <updated>2009-02-20T00:10:10-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.goingthewongway.com/bowling-high</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Late breaking news, this just in.  I got my highest score ever in bowling recently.  While playing a game in the midst of bowling all I could for $5, I accomplished a feat that I thought not possible.  The bowling alley was old school, and we had to score our own games (it's amazing how few people know how to score bowling without a computer).  Still I think that the picture speaks for itself:</p>

<p><img src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3253/3288294781_3f6118082e.jpg" alt="Scored 205!" /></p>

<p>Lest you think that I am amazing at bowling, the score that I got the previous game was 98 thank you very much.  I must also say, though, that I didn't bowl my own third frame.  If I did, who knows what great and earth-shattering things might have happened!</p>

<p>Also, I got sore from bowling that much.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[NBA Playoffs (Final Thoughts)]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/nba-playoffs-final-thoughts/"/>
    <updated>2007-06-15T13:15:56-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.goingthewongway.com/nba-playoffs-final-thoughts</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This was originally going to be titled "NBA Playoffs (Thus Far Commentary #3)," but the Cleveland Cavaliers lost faster than I could write this post.</p>

<p>The Cavs were no match for the Spurs.  The real finals happened in the West, probably the Suns vs Spurs series.  LeBron James gets a lot of attention, but Tony Parker was the one who tore it up.  I said as much before the series started that Parker was going to be their downfall.</p>

<p>This was one of the least interesting finals series in a long time.  Instead of watching game 4 last night, I just decided to wash my truck.</p>

<p>The Cavs were so over matched they couldn't even pull out 1 game (granted, they were close a couple of times).  Even the Lakers took one from the Suns!  How's that for an insult?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[NBA Playoffs (Thus Far Commentary #2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/nba-playoffs-thus-far-commentary-2/"/>
    <updated>2007-05-16T19:30:16-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.goingthewongway.com/nba-playoffs-thus-far-commentary-2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Well of course things go on, so I wanted to write my thoughts at this junction about the NBA Playoffs 2007.</p>

<p>I was hoping that the <strong>Golden State Warriors</strong> would get farther than the second round.  However I became ambivalent as Baron Davis' personality (as well as Stephen Jackson's) came out.  That elbow to Derek Fisher's face?  Unnecessary to the extreme.  To say that I gained a lot and lost a lot of respect for the Warriors would be fair to say.  I enjoyed their playing because they were passionate and energetic.  I started to disapprove of them because many of them turned out to be a bunch of no-class, cocky-without-rights-to, complaining-to-no-end players.  And that is not a team that I want to cheer for.  So they're out, and good riddance.</p>

<p>A lot of people disliked <strong>Derek Fisher</strong> when he was on the Lakers.  I never felt as strongly about him.  In fact, I kind of liked him.  He had spirit and he played hard.  Plus we share the same first name.  He's by no means the best at his position, but he's definitely shown in the Jazz vs Warriors series that he's got lots left in that tank.  To see him also having to deal with everything going on with his daughter makes him an especially easy-to-cheer-for player.  Bravo on being an impact player in the series.</p>

<p>There sure has been a lot of <strong>testiness</strong> in these playoffs.  Is it just me or does it seem like there is more this year than in recent history?  Pretty much every series has had some episode of a flareup.  LeBron is stepping up, the Pistons are never exactly clean, the aforementioned Warriors and Jazz got it on, and of course the Suns and the Spurs have no love lost for their fellow Texans.  It all makes for exciting and emotional games, but I kind of wonder why this year is so.</p>

<p>I'm cheering for the <strong>Chicago Bulls</strong> to beat the Pistons.  I'm not a huge Bulls fan, but I have enjoyed watching them play this year.  Unfortunately they seem like they go very cold at times, and that led to the Pistons taking a (seemingly) insurmountable 3-0 series lead on them.  They've fought back to 3-2, and everyone has been singing their praise.  I'd like to see them down the vaunted Pistons myself.</p>

<p>I barely even hear or see much from the <strong>Cleveland Cavaliers</strong> side of the bracket.  The Wizards series went down very quietly.  It's no surprise, but the West seems to definitely be the better conference.</p>

<p><strong>Robert Horry's forearm to Nash's face</strong> was pretty poor.  I always kind of liked Horry because I enjoyed his late-game heroics.  I'm not really sure what the beef between the Suns and the Spurs is, but I know this: they don't like each other.  I'm not a fan of many of them myself.  Many of them (Manu Ginobili, Bruce Bowen, Raja Bell to name a few) are aggressive bordering on extremely dirty.  And that's no good.  But I like watching the series because both of these teams are pretty good.  They have different styles but they both have multiple superstars who combine to do amazing things sometimes.</p>

<h3>Conclusion</h3>

<p>The NBA Playoffs 2007 are definitely interesting.  I like seeing people get emotional, but there's no need to be a jerk about things.  Keep it coming.  I'm going to enjoy watching more.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[NBA Playoffs (Thus Far Commentary #1)]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/nba-playoffs-thus-far-commentary-1/"/>
    <updated>2007-05-02T12:39:23-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.goingthewongway.com/nba-playoffs-thus-far-commentary-1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3>Chicago Bulls vs Miami Heat</h3>

<p>You've gotta hand it to the Bulls, they can roll.  I enjoyed watching them tear up the Heat.  Although I don't think that I hold any ill feelings toward Shaquille O'Neal for leaving the Lakers, I'm not a big Heat fan.  I'm not even sure what it is.  I just don't really care for them.  I think that Wade is overrated (although good), and the rest of the team is just a bunch of cocky goons (namely Antoine Walker).</p>

<h3>Golden State Warriors vs Dallas Mavericks</h3>

<p>Though never really a fan of the Warriors, I've also never really been opposed to them.  I've enjoyed watching their series against the Mavericks.  However, I thought it quite disappointing that they couldn't close out against them last night with a <strong>nine</strong> point lead with a few minutes left!  That's too bad.  I'm a fan of how strong Baron Davis and Jason Richardson are playing.  I'm not really a fan of Stephen Jackson because I think that he's a crybaby.  And Al Harrington?  Forgot to show up.  Here's hoping that they close it out for real next time and send Mark Cuban &amp; Co. packing.</p>

<h3>Los Angeles Lakers vs Phoenix Suns</h3>

<p>I'll always be a fan of the Lakers.  But they have been straight-up disappointing nearly the entire year!  Kobe is pretty amazing sometimes (everyone <em>has</em> to admit that), but he both can't do everything and can't always be so amazing.  Until they either get a real team or they learn to work together consistently, they won't ever get very far in the playoffs.  All of the other teams are just too good to monkey around every night.  I'll be cheering for the Suns in a week (even though they talked a little too much before the series started about how they'd steamroll the Lakers).</p>

<h3>Cleveland Cavaliers vs Washington Wizards</h3>

<p>I watched part of the game on Sunday.  I fell asleep.  That's pretty much all you need to know about this series.</p>

<h3>Denver Nuggets vs San Antonio Spurs</h3>

<p>I thought the Nuggets could pull something off, especially after the first game.  But the Spurs seem relentless.  And Robert Horry must dream throughout the entire season about making those big playoff shots.  The series isn't that close, but it's still fairly entertaining.</p>

<h3>New Jersey Nets vs Toronto Raptors</h3>

<p>I think the Nets should have been finished with the series already.</p>

<h3>Orlando Magic vs Detroit Pistons</h3>

<p>Why did they even have to play this series?  I thought they would be better.  But the Magic players never showed up at the same time.  Something must have been wrong with their alarm clocks.  Maybe they need five alarms.</p>

<h3>Houston Rockets vs Utah Jazz</h3>

<p>Rooting for the Rockets.  They have showed glimpses of how far they could go with their 1-2 combo of McGrady and Yao.  However, it hasn't been consistent enough to knock out the Jazz yet.  Chinese guy?  I'm for the Rockets.  Plus they've got <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rafer_Alston">Skip To My Lou</a>!  You've gotta cheer for that guy.  Even if he does have the worst Field Goal % in the NBA.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
