<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Money | Going The Wong Way]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/categories/money/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-04-23T21:11:41-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.goingthewongway.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Derek Wong]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Paying For Software]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/paying-for-software/"/>
    <updated>2011-06-16T01:14:37-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.goingthewongway.com/paying-for-software</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I am a big fan of <a href="http://www.gnu.org/philosophy/free-sw.html">free software</a> so it is no surprise that I use and advocate it when I can.  I would not consider myself <a href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/10/fanaticism/">fanatical</a> about it (i.e., I will and do use non-free software).  However, in my experience and observation I have noticed how difficult it is for people to pay for software.  How else can you explain how we can pay hundreds to thousands of dollars for a computer only to refuse to pay $20 for a particular desired application?</p>

<p>It seems that people are confused about developers, especially those that create free software.  Maybe they do not think that the developers are entitled to compensation because they are releasing free software.  I guess that in part it is due to the difference between the definitions of free (as in zero cost) and free (as in liberty).  Software developers are (surprise!) real people that need to make a living as well.  In a world that contains both free (as in zero cost) and free (as in liberty) software, people need to understand both in order for them to see where the software developer is coming from.  So perhaps we can all remember that paying for software should be seen just like we should view all other purchases - if it satisfies our requirements for purchasing then we should go ahead and do that.</p>

<p>All of these words when this abbreviated comic (originally <a href="http://theoatmeal.com/blog/apps">here</a>) says it perhaps even better:</p>

<p><img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/theoatmeal-img/comics/apps/3.png" alt="Buying an expensive iPhone" /><img src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/theoatmeal-img/comics/apps/5.png" alt="Cannot buy paid app" /></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Getting Paid Under The Table]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/getting-paid-under-the-table/"/>
    <updated>2010-08-05T01:53:23-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.goingthewongway.com/getting-paid-under-the-table</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Lately I feel like I have been encountering people who are getting paid under the table, which means that they are being paid in a way that attempts to circumvent tax laws.  Basically whoever is paying them is not reporting that payment as wages and that means that they are not liable for their share of the tax to the government.  The person being paid has the benefit of also not being subject to tax for that payment amount, which effectively means that everyone is keeping more money for themselves.</p>

<p>Unfortunately there is a loser in this transaction.  And that loser is everyone else.  Everyone who <strong>does</strong> pay their taxes loses because:</p>

<ol>
<li>they could be paying less</li>
<li>they could receive more benefits if everyone paid their taxes</li>
<li>the national debt (which at the time of writing stands at over $13 trillion - <a href="http://www.brillig.com/debt_clock/">check it out</a>) could be lower</li>
</ol>


<p>Instead it is left to the taxpayers to pick up their slack.  Yes, even though they (the ones involved in this nefarious transaction) are likely working members of society who do not see themselves as being a burden (they are making their own money after all), their presence on the roads, need for protection (e.g., police, fire), and receipt of other benefits are proof that they have an impact on us.</p>

<p>Integrity?  Yeah why don't we go for that.  Or at the absolute very least, acknowledge and label black as black and white as white.  It is not something to be proud of (and neither is stealing lunch money from a child).</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[For The Love Of The Game]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/for-the-love-of-the-game/"/>
    <updated>2009-01-05T00:21:21-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.goingthewongway.com/for-the-love-of-the-game</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I do enjoy myself some National Basketball Association.  The <a href="http://www.nba.com/lakers/">Los Angeles Lakers</a> have been doing fairly well, and I must say that I'm happy about that.  If you're wondering, I'm not a band wagon fan unlike many other people in southern California!</p>

<p>Sometimes, though, I stop and think about the marketing for the NBA.  "I love this game"??  Yeah, I'm sure that they love it so much.  But what if they weren't getting paid millions of dollars to play it?  What if they only made the <a href="http://www.census.gov/Press-Release/www/releases/archives/income_wealth/012528.html">average salary of an American in 2007</a>, which is $50,233?  Okay let's be generous and just go with an even $100,000.  I doubt that we would get the talent that we have now because people wouldn't devote their entire lives to getting better at the sport.  Parents would force their kids to go through endless numbers of camps and drills in order to just get that perfect arc on their shot.  They definitely wouldn't spend every moment of the day in a gym.  Well at least not the majority of them.  I'm sure that some of them would still work just as hard because they really do love the game.  But I'm sure that some of them would have to pursue other more lucrative careers that they could be successful at (such as rapping or investment banking).</p>

<p>Love the game?  Yeah, not so much.</p>

<p>How is it that we live in a world where the player of a game (which I admittedly enjoy watching and participating in) can make many many times the amount of money of someone who is saving lives as a fireman?  Or putting their lives on the line as policemen.  Or helping the downtrodden.  Money sure isn't a direct correlation to importance in the grand scheme of things, is it?</p>

<p>How inequitable!  But what else can I expect from a world tainted by sin?
  *[NBA]: National Basketball Association, I thought that I already said that!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Driving ~ Playing The Stock Market]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/driving-playing-the-stock-market/"/>
    <updated>2008-07-31T01:15:09-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.goingthewongway.com/driving-playing-the-stock-market</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Lots of people drive.  Although perhaps we should rethink the way that we do it, what with the amount of money we're sinking into our traveling.  While there is much to think about (least of all are my <a href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/2008/07/16/tips-for-saving-gas/">Tips For Saving Gas</a>), you can also find lessons that aren't initially obvious.  And by you, I mean me.</p>

<p>Driving everyday to work has taught me a few things.  One thing that I've recently noticed is how it seems to me that I need to just chill when I'm driving.  That is, it does no good to constantly switch lanes in order to try to get ahead.  While I may get ahead a little bit, just a single wrong choice, and I've lost all that I've worked so hard to get.</p>

<p>So it is with stocks as well.</p>

<ul>
<li><p>Fairly common advice is that you should buy for the long term.  The extra stress, work, and volatility are said to just not be worth it.  That is, you could do all of that work and still end up at the same place as someone who just set it and left it.  And that definitely happens to people when they're switching lanes trying to get around all of the other people.  It's perhaps even more noticeable since a good deal of the road that I drive is 2 lanes.</p></li>
<li><p>Don't be shocked if something abruptly happens to you.  If you're going someplace and you need to be on time, isn't it always better to be early and prepared rather than cutting it as close as possible?  That way, if something happens, you'll have some leeway to recover.  And don't you dare go putting all over your money into 1 stock.  Or even all of your money into stocks!</p></li>
<li><p>Notice patterns.  When driving the same route everyday, I start to get a sense of how things are.  That is, some lanes are more apt to progress more quickly because of the traffic flow.  And I start to notice how lights are set up so I know whether it's worth it to bust my butt to make the light.  Alright so maybe that's hard to make into some lesson for stocks because the whole deal with the stock market is that people are trying to predict what companies are going to do.  And it's only partially based on past performance.  Still, take that past into account when doing your stock-picking thing.</p></li>
</ul>


<p>The comparison doesn't hold up completely, of course.  While you don't <em>have</em> to buy stocks, you do have to pick a lane to drive in.  But you know what?  I'm not concerning myself with making a perfect comparison.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Contests With Prizes Are Great]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/contests-with-prizes-are-great/"/>
    <updated>2007-10-04T13:20:50-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.goingthewongway.com/contests-with-prizes-are-great</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I'm a little slow on this news, but one of the sites that I subscribe and read (<a href="http://www.problogger.net">ProBlogger.net</a>) is having a contest to celebrate the anniversary of his blog.  You can find more details of it all at <a href="http://www.problogger.net/archives/2007/10/02/54000-worth-of-prizes-on-offer-in-the-problogger-birthday-bash-competitions/">the competition page</a>.  There are $54,000 worth of prizes to be had in a number of smaller contests (although admittedly some of the contests are already done).  Many of them are fairly easy to participate in.</p>

<p>So check it out because remember: the possibility of winning is better than no possibility at all!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
