<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: News | Going The Wong Way]]></title>
  <link href="http://dwong.github.com/categories/news/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://dwong.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-09-21T06:06:06-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://dwong.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Derek Wong]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Do It, Arnold]]></title>
    <link href="http://dwong.github.com/do-it-arnold/"/>
    <updated>2009-07-01T01:14:13-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://dwong.github.com/do-it-arnold</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The whole situation with the California budget crisis is ridiculous.  It is looking very likely that <a href="http://www.reuters.com/article/topNews/idUSTRE55T7E120090630">California will have to issue IOUs</a> as the new fiscal year rolls around.  How did we get into this pickle?  The recession!  The decreased revenue from falling property taxes and lack of state income taxes from those who are not working has left the Golden State in a huge predicament.  $24.3 BILLION??  That is ridiculous.</p>

<p>In the special election on May 19, 2009, the people of this state voted against the increased taxes that were proposed.  I am a fairly modest supporter of our <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Arnold_Schwarzenegger">Governator</a> as he is standing against the tide.  I agree with his observation that the people of California are sick and tired of living in the most taxed state of the United States of America!  Even though he has not always been my favorite politician (really who is?), I am glad that he is attempting to stand for what he thinks that the people want.</p>

<p>Democratic state politicians on the other hard are, inexplicably, ridiculous.  While they, too, are trying to stand for what they think that the people want, they are doing it in a way that is illogical.  From trying to find loopholes to pass the budget with a simple majority (since they can't pass what they want without Republican support) to trying to pass tax increases along with budget cuts, they are not making the process extremely difficult.  They are still trying to get theirs while seeming to not understand what basic tasks they need to do in order to get the state's finances in order.</p>

<p>Let us put it simply: California <strong>needs</strong> to cut its costs.  It doesn't have the money and at this point it is not reasonable to increase the taxes that it imposes on its population.  At some point people are going to get tired of paying so much for the privilege of wonderful weather (and horrible smog).  I wonder if the politicians know this.  Maybe good old Mr. Olympia himself knows.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cheatin' Chinese]]></title>
    <link href="http://dwong.github.com/cheatin-chinese/"/>
    <updated>2007-05-04T11:08:17-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://dwong.github.com/cheatin-chinese</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Sometimes Chinese people do good things.  Sometimes Chinese people do bad things.  And sometimes Chinese people sure do some stupid things.</p>

<p>Get this: Chinese people copied Disneyland.  As in, they made a Disneyland <strong>park</strong>.  Are you kidding me?!</p>

<p>I read <a href="http://www.engadget.com/2007/05/04/keepin-it-real-fake-part-lv-disneyland/">an Engadget article about the fake Disneyland</a> that got me to searching for more information.  Amusingly, they have characters that closely mimic the Disney ones as well as rides that indicate how much of a fake it is.  Their slogan (according to <a href="http://www.thestandard.com.hk/news_detail.asp?pp_cat=20&amp;art_id=41990&amp;sid=13078355&amp;con_type=1&amp;d_str=20070411">this other article</a>) is that "Disneyland is too far."  Wow, that is unbelievable.  I think that actually the most amusing thing about Beijing's Shijingshan Amusement Park is that its website is <a href="http://www.bs-amusement-park.com">http://www.bs-amusement-park.com</a>.  Haha you read that right, it's the BS amusement park.</p>

<p>Although pretty humorous, this actually touches on a more serious issue (which was touched on at <a href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/2007/04/14/even-worse-than-at-first-glance/">Even Worse Than At First Glance</a>).  And that issue is copyright infringement (or in this case complete disregard for copyrights whatsoever).</p>

<p>links:
<a href="http://www.thestandard.com.hk/news_detail.asp?pp_cat=20&amp;art_id=41990&amp;sid=13078355&amp;con_type=1&amp;d_str=20070411">The Standard (Chinese business newspaper) article</a> - Touches the most on the significant copyright issues
<a href="http://www.engadget.com/2007/05/04/keepin-it-real-fake-part-lv-disneyland/">Engadget article</a> - Amusing pictures
<a href="http://www.rcdb.com/pd609.htm">Roller Coaster Database</a> - Park information, list of rides, etc
<a href="http://www.bs-amusement-park.com">Actual Disneyland-clone website</a> - I don't know Chinese (the language), but if you do then the story might get even more amusing for you</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Car Salesmen Definitely Earn Their Reputation]]></title>
    <link href="http://dwong.github.com/car-salesmen-definitely-earn-their-reputation/"/>
    <updated>2007-04-25T11:30:15-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://dwong.github.com/car-salesmen-definitely-earn-their-reputation</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Do you like car salesmen?  I don't.</p>

<p>They're pushy, they're slightly overbearing, and they only want to be your friends to make money off of you.</p>

<p>Case in point:</p>

<p>I read an article about an incident that outraged me.  It also solidified my distaste for car salesmen.  In the May 2007 edition of <a href="http://www.caranddriver.com/">Car and Driver</a> magazine, I saw an article about a man who went into a dealership to buy a car.  He ended up buying a GMC Canyon.  This man was mentally disabled (he was later reported to have had feces-covered pants on) with a reported IQ (from a relative) of 70.</p>

<p>To buy the Canyon, the man paid in cash (approximately $30,000) and ended up telling the salesman that he actually had a lot more cash at home.  Granted this isn't exactly a wise thing to do, but this man was also understandably mentally disabled.</p>

<p>Events proceeded and the man one day thought that his truck had been stolen (when in fact it turned out to have been towed).  He called up his salesman buddy for a ride who then took him to the tow yard.  While driving him, the other salesmen who had conspired together proceeded to go to the man's home and steal the money.  They ended up leaving with $70,000.</p>

<p>The police then came to the house to investigate the crime and upon finding feces throughout the house, had the mentally disabled man committed to an institute.  A salesman kindly took the time to go to the institute, get the man to sign over the Canyon to <em>him</em>, and charged him for the time that it took to do so!</p>

<p>Subsequently, lawsuits were brought against many of the salesmen, the dealership returned the $100,000 to the man, and some semblance of justice was served.</p>

<p>Suffice to say, I am still not impressed with salesmen.  <strong>Especially</strong> those of the car variety.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Man Cuts It Off In Restaurant]]></title>
    <link href="http://dwong.github.com/man-cuts-it-off-in-restaurant/"/>
    <updated>2007-04-24T14:45:07-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://dwong.github.com/man-cuts-it-off-in-restaurant</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>People are ridiculous.  It's amazing.  I don't even need to cut this entry short because I am speechless at such an act.  Imagine yourself out eating dinner at a nice place.  Then a man runs in.  And then that man proceeds to storm a kitchen, grab a knife, and cut himself.  Even more shockingly, he cuts off his own penis.  Are you kidding me?!</p>

<p>If you'd like, you can read <a href="http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/england/london/6586879.stm">the original article</a>.  Seen <a href="http://digg.com/world_news/Man_cuts_off_penis_in_restaurant_2">on Digg</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
