<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Humor | Going The Wong Way]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/categories/humor/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-02-12T07:56:10-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.goingthewongway.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Derek Wong]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Crom, The One Who Can't Concentrate With Too Much Noise]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/crom-the-one-who-cant-concentrate-with-too-much-noise/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-07T21:30:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.goingthewongway.com/crom-the-one-who-cant-concentrate-with-too-much-noise</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Crom is a man who works early.<br/>
He definitely does not have hair that's curly.<br/>
He likes to have <a href="/crom-the-one-who-loveshates-his-girlfriend/">interesting</a> chats.<br/>
I highly doubt he works out the lats.<br/></p>

<p>He is quite a unique one, that Crom is.<br/>
Of that I am telling the truth, I promise.<br/>
He walks about with a full bowl of food,<br/>
And <a href="/crom-the-one-who-cuts-his-toenails-at-work/">does things</a> that some might think of as rude.<br/></p>

<p>He tells bad jokes<br/>
To most any of the folks.<br/>
Worst of all when it's about work and he's on the phone<br/>
He tells me and my friends to lower our tone.<br/></p>

<p>It's very strange since there are rooms.<br/>
I mean, you can't make noise like you can in the <a href="/crom-the-loud-one/">restrooms</a>.<br/>
At the least he can watch out to not be so loud,<br/>
But that lack of self-examination is what sets him apart from the crowd.<br/></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[On Going On A Date (Guy Version)]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/on-going-on-a-date-guy-version/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-28T00:21:54-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.goingthewongway.com/on-going-on-a-date-guy-version</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Take this list and write it down.  Believe in it.  Win it.  Done and done, happily ever after.</p>

<ol>
<li><strong>Wing It</strong> - This is especially important early on.  Everyone likes a man who can improvise.  It's probably just better to ask her what she wants to do when you pick her up.  Since you know, she might be very particular about the food she eats, the activities that she does, and so on and so forth.  So don't plan anything specific because it will just be a waste of your time.</li>
<li><strong>Split The Bill</strong> - This is the modern age.  Women are the equal of men.  And you know what that means!  She wants you to treat her like an equal.  Plus you know, it might not work out.  Either way you get to save more of your hard-earned money in the process.</li>
<li><strong>Have Her Drive</strong> - She probably likes driving anyway.  This will let her practice since girls aren't as good at driving.  Oh and you're going to do whatever she wants anyway.  So really, everyone wins.</li>
<li><strong>Avoid Talking As Much As Possible</strong> - Just stare.  She's beautiful, huh?  Talking isn't necessary.  She'll be won over by your style, charisma, and wonderful cologne.</li>
<li><strong>Talk About Yourself</strong> - When you do have to talk (e.g., she asks you a question) then just make sure to keep the topic of conversation on something that you know.  And what do you know better than yourself and your favorite things?</li>
<li><strong>Come On Strong</strong> - Only the serious-minded know that the secret to winning the girl is to either go laid back cool or full-court press.  So if you are going to the latter route then you better go all of the way.  5 course candle-lit dinner, sunset walk on the beach, hired Mariachi band,  horse-drawn carriage.  Go big or go home, buddy.  Everything that you see in those romantic comedies is fair game.  Failing those things, <em>at the very least</em> contact her early and often after the date.  Show her how much you want more.  She'll reciprocate I'm sure.</li>
</ol>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Crom, The One Who Loves/Hates His Girlfriend]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/crom-the-one-who-loveshates-his-girlfriend/"/>
    <updated>2011-11-15T01:10:39-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.goingthewongway.com/crom-the-one-who-loveshates-his-girlfriend</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So we know that Crom <a href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/914/crom-the-one-with-the-girlfriend/">has a girlfriend</a>.  It seems like he likes her a lot.  He talks to her on a very frequent basis as far as I can tell.  I rather wish that I did not observe so much about him!</p>

<p>From what I can recall, he talks to her at least twice a day.  Every.  Single.  Day.  The weird thing is that I get the impression that they also see each other quite often (I would guess 4 times a week).  Is that the weirdest thing?  No not by a long shot.  There are plenty of people out there who cannot get enough of seeing and talking to each other.  And I am sure that there are plenty of middle-aged men with girlfriends out there as well.</p>

<p>No, the weirdest thing is the fact that when he talks to her it is sugar, honey, lovey, and dovey for a little while.  You know what I mean.  He has his boyfriend voice (ugh, I feel gross just typing that) and talks softly and gently while saying nice things.  However, for whatever reason this almost always turns on a dime, and he seems to get very irritated/impatient with her.  He will start to tell her the things that she needs to do (e.g., get out of bed and get ready for work) or he will quickly bail out on the conversation (e.g., I really need to get back to work).</p>

<p>I know that no couple is perfect because <strong>nobody is perfect</strong>.  So it is not that strange that they could have this conversation every so often.  However it does seem strange to me that it seems to happen every time that they talk.  And remember, they talk a couple of times a day everyday!  I have no idea what it is about these people!  I have so many questions.  Why does he do it?  Why does she put up with it?  Why are they still together after all of this time??</p>

<p>Perhaps he is starting to feel guilty about using work time for personal reasons.  Perhaps he just gets tired of talking on the phone.  (Now mind  you he usually just stays out here in the cubicles while he is talking so everyone can hear his conversation.)</p>

<p>Whatever the reason, I guess that we'll just have to chalk it up to another mystery of <a href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/tag/crom/">Crom</a>.  I doubt that I could ever understand.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Crom, The Loud One]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/crom-the-loud-one/"/>
    <updated>2010-11-08T00:20:53-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.goingthewongway.com/crom-the-loud-one</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>There are plenty of loud people in the world.  That is not surprising.  But it is surprising when Crom is loud in the bathroom because I am of a particular opinion that most people try to be discrete there.  And he can do this no matter what he is doing in the bathroom.</p>

<p>He will walk in loudly as if he is in a rush.  He whistles and hums.</p>

<p>As he is urinating it is as if he is using all of his might to expel the liquid from his system.  Oddly enough, it seems as if there is air in the line since it will go full force then halt entirely then back to full force.  Even more odd is the fact that I have always thought that going full force (as he does) would result in more splash-back (if you know what I mean).  After expelling the liquid, he seems to like to let out a loud sigh of relief.  The sound makes me think that he is being intimate with the urinal.  That is just the sound that I want to be hearing from him.  Ew.  Just ew.  After that I sometimes <em>very</em> unfortunately do <strong>not</strong> hear the sound of the faucet.  Quadruple ew.</p>

<p>Now on the other hand, there are times when he poops.  I mean, <a href="http://amzn.to/Rs69nc">everyone does</a>.  And those times are pretty loud as well.  But that's because he pushes that stuff out of his butt with as much force as he can.  At least that's what it seems like!  I can also discern that there is no toilet seat cover or toilet paper used to cover the seat.  Good thing he washes his hands after using the stall.</p>

<p>Welcome to the bathroom world of Crom.  It is a very unpleasant place for the rest of us.  He probably does not know about <a href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/176/on-bathroom-behavior/">some of my opinions about the bathroom</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Crom, The One Without License Plates]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/crom-the-one-without-license-plates/"/>
    <updated>2010-07-13T01:32:25-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.goingthewongway.com/crom-the-one-without-license-plates</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Crom bought a new hybrid vehicle approximately 1 year ago.  When he bought it I could not help but overhear him proclaiming its merits.  He talked about how it had all of the latest gadgets, of which I believe the only one that I actually heard him specifically mention was the Bluetooth.  The same song came out of his mouth for the whole week.  Not a big deal.  Everyone gets excited when we get a new possession, right?  Lately I doubt that he has been as excited about it.  It's a Toyota after all.</p>

<p>After a year of owning the car, he still does not have license plates on it.  It appears to those who do not know that it is a new car.  When I noticed that this was happening (it's hard not to notice after a few months) I was very curious as to why someone would want to do this.  My pondering led me to the following:</p>

<ol>
<li>The license plates that he received were 6BAD666, 1SAD120, etc or which he otherwise found offensive.</li>
<li>He is in love with the dealer that sold him his vehicle</li>
<li>Now he has the ability to run red lights or drive toll roads without paying</li>
<li>He desires to remain as unique as possible (i.e., a recently purchased Toyota)</li>
<li>He actually purchases a new model of the same car every couple of months</li>
<li>The Department of Motor Vehicles has made its first ever mistake</li>
</ol>


<p>I am of a mind to tear his precious new car papers just to see what happens.  Or maybe just draw a happy face with a Sharpie marker.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
