<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: political | Going The Wong Way]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/categories/political/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-04-08T20:55:58-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.goingthewongway.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Derek Wong]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[When Selfishness Surpasses Logic]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/when-selfishness-surpasses-logic/"/>
    <updated>2013-12-07T11:10:32-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.goingthewongway.com/when-selfishness-surpasses-logic</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I was out for lunch on a Sunday afternoon in Chinatown.  The restaurant that my group went to was mostly full, but we were able to get a table in a back room.  It wasn&rsquo;t ideally placed since it was awkwardly positioned relative to another large table, but it was definitely better than having to wait.  I sat near the large table with my back to it and at some point later on in the meal my lunch mates indicated for me to look behind me.  Lo and behold there was an elderly Chinese woman sitting with her chair positioned so that I could not move back any further.  This wouldn&rsquo;t be a problem if that&rsquo;s what the proximity of our tables required, but she was so far from her table that she couldn&rsquo;t touch it if she wanted to.  In fact I&rsquo;m not sure if she could have touched the people who were sitting at the table!  She had taken it upon herself to reserve as much space for her table as possible.  Oh fantastic.</p>

<p>As we concluded and left our lunch, my group discussed this.  What amazed us most was the fact that she would make herself so uncomfortable to do what she did.  In the end, she was able to reserve some extra breathing room for her lunch mates even though she had put herself out of sorts.  However, the extra breathing room is pretty useless if you already have plenty of breathing room!  Ultimately I am losing, she is losing, and her tablemates are not really gaining anything of use.</p>

<p>In a small personal context this doesn&rsquo;t make sense.  Nor does it in a larger social sense.  Getting cheap/free healthcare is going to cost all of the rest of the people more (whether reduced benefits or higher cost).  For you to get more, others must get less.  There is no magic fountain of money and benefits.  Would you pursue more if ultimately getting more meant that everyone got nothing?  What if everything collapsed because everyone was getting something for free?  Was it worth it?  Is your pension worth it if governments go bankrupt?  Is it even worth anything at that point?</p>

<p>Take what you&rsquo;re doing and think about the consequences.  You might not like what you find.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Big Government]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/big-government/"/>
    <updated>2010-08-18T01:31:29-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.goingthewongway.com/big-government</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Lately I have been reading and enjoying <a href="http://biggovernment.com/">Big Government</a>, which is a website created by Andrew Breitbart.  It is a website that advocates a smaller government by exposing the ways that the government is improperly doing things.  It is definitely enlightening because the articles attempt to show the readers ways that our very own federal government (of the United States of America) are doing things that most of us would very likely disapprove of.  And boy do we!  (Or at least&hellip;I do.)  Compounding the problem is that many of these things do not even seem legal in light of the <a href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/512/10th-amendment/">10th amendment</a>!</p>

<p>This isn&rsquo;t a long post and really I am not adding anything to the collective knowledge or opinion of the Internet.  However I have been enjoying some of the videos that I have seen there and would therefore like to share:</p>

<ul>
<li></li>
<li></li>
<li></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Political Corruption: Pork Barrel]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/political-corruption-pork-barrel/"/>
    <updated>2010-07-01T01:24:56-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.goingthewongway.com/political-corruption-pork-barrel</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Pork is delicious when it means the consumed meat from a pig.  Conversely it is awful when it refers to the appropriations of government money for local projects.  While I might be a big supporter of the former, let&rsquo;s not forget that the late Senator Robert Byrd was a huge proponent of the latter.</p>

<p>When he passed, I heard a radio commentator quote an unnamed source from West Virginia saying that they would not know what to do now that he wasn&rsquo;t in Washington to send federal funds back to them.  It makes sense for them to think this way because he sent back billions to them during his tenure (Citizens Against Government Waste has a <a href="http://www.cagw.org/newsroom/byrd-pork-tally.html">tally of Senator Byrd&rsquo;s pork</a> that will boggle the mind).  So it is true, they just lost a major source of income.  What&rsquo;s a person to do?!  I have an idea: start making your own way instead of swiping money from the rest of the country.</p>

<p>I am sure that the people of West Virginia are not the only ones.  There are recipients of pork everywhere, and they should all be ashamed.  This corruption needs to stop.  We all know that politicians are self-serving, power-hungry individuals.  Do not feed them your vote <strong>or</strong> willingly eat their pork!  Does anyone think about the fact that the politicians are taking money from everyone else just so that they can remain in office?  It seems like pork barrel politics could also be called much much worse.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Government Union]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/the-government-union/"/>
    <updated>2009-12-12T00:40:33-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.goingthewongway.com/the-government-union</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have frequently heard people advocating government jobs.  That is, the people that I know will talk about how good it is to be a government employee.  They talk about the pension, benefits, and job security, to name a few.  All of these things are true.  But just as the <a href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/519/unions-will-get-you-for-sure/">unions</a> will get you in the private sector, so also will the unions affect the public sector.  Sometimes the unions in the government are organized, but one could make a case for the entire federal government being one gigantic union that stands against their employer (aka the American people).</p>

<p>In a <a href="http://www.usatoday.com/news/washington/2009-12-10-federal-pay-salaries_N.htm">USA Today article</a>, we find out that things are in fact not too good.  People are being paid quite a bit nowadays, don&rsquo;t you think?  It is especially interesting that there has been such a boom in government increases during the same time as the private sector losing so many jobs.  And by interesting I mean awfully disturbing.  The government is becoming a behemoth that is going to continue growing until it collapses and knocks down the support columns that hold up this house.</p>

<p>The thing that I do not understand in the least is how people in government positions can work without the fear of being fired!  Whether incompetent or able, they will keep their job (unless perhaps they are grossly ill-performing where even then it will take quite some effort to make a move on them).  So when people are presented with the option to try their best or do as little as possible with both seeming to result in the same outcome, what would people do?  Exactly, they would do the least possible.  There is no incentive for people in government jobs to continue to do their best.  Now you see what I am saying about the government employees being similar to a union.</p>

<p>Just as the unions have been able to cripple portions of the private sector (such as the American automakers), it is going to be the government employees that are going to bring down the government.  If you have not read what unions can do to the world, I suggest that you read the ever popular <em><a href="http://amzn.to/PuUYqb">Atlas Shrugged</a></em> by Ayn Rand.</p>

<p>All of the signs are there.  <a href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/675/health-care-reform/">Health care reform</a> that will dictate much more than we need or want it to, a growing government influence in our lives, a government that dictates what companies will do (since it owns them), perhaps even the degradation of freedoms to which we are rightly entitled to under the Constitution.  This is something that concerns all of us, and we all need to care about it.  Because we sure are going to have the live with the consequences together.  And disregarding warning is a terribly foolhardy thing to do.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Health Care Reform]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/health-care-reform/"/>
    <updated>2009-10-09T01:10:07-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.goingthewongway.com/health-care-reform</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Nobody likes to pay for health services.  And health services are not perfect at all.  They (medical professionals) charge more than what seems reasonable, and they do not seem to have to answer to anybody except for the health insurance companies because they only listen to the money.  It would be nice to have personal doctors and nurses to tend to your every whim.  And it would be nice if you did not have to pay anything for it.</p>

<p>But this is not how the world works.  For one, medical professionals are people as well.  I am talking about doctors, not the rank and file like staff and assistants.  These are individuals who have gone to school, invested hours and nights to their profession.  (Well at least I hope that they have.  The ones that have not are not ones that I would ever want to go to.)  Their work is indeed important, and it is at times worth the cost.</p>

<p>People sometimes claim that a single entity watching over the entire operation here in the United States will be more efficient.  More efficient?  Since when did a government project ever win awards for efficiency??  Yeah that&rsquo;s a pretty crazy <a href="http://docs.house.gov/gopleader/House-Democrats-Health-Plan.pdf">health plan chart</a>, isn&rsquo;t it?  It is only a guess at what the new health government would look like, but it sure is a scary one.</p>

<p>If everyone has access to all of the doctors, people are going to take as much as they can.  Do you think that you will get to pay the best doctor what he/she is charging?  Well when everything costs the same for everyone it just logically follows that the best doctors are going to be as busy as people can schedule appointments.  People dismiss the supposed &ldquo;death panels&rdquo; that will decide on life and death decisions for everyone, but if there is a shortage of supply (doctors) compared to the increase in demand (patients) then some of those patients will have to be left out.  There is just no possible other way for that outcome to be different.</p>

<p>It is pretty debatable whether or not other countries have succeeded at this or not.  That is not really the question.  The question is: do I really want to cede more control over my life to the federal government?  To that I say no, I am still a huge fan of the <a href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/512/10th-amendment/">10th amendment</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
