<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Life | Going The Wong Way]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/categories/life/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-03-15T09:29:49-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.goingthewongway.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Derek Wong]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Do You Believe In Luck?]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/do-you-believe-in-luck/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-08T18:15:58-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.goingthewongway.com/do-you-believe-in-luck</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Luck is a strange thing.  People believe that it&rsquo;s out there helping or hurting them.  They believe that it is a force to be reckoned with.  With countless other things in the world people take to rationalism.  They deny spirituality, mysticism, and definitely things like Christianity.  But all around us people have ideas ingrained in their minds about luck.  Some examples:</p>

<ul>
<li>You dare not shave your <a href="http://go.gtww.net/1iavCMf">playoff beard</a></li>
<li>Saying &ldquo;good luck&rdquo; to someone before they go on stage for a performance</li>
<li>Don&rsquo;t do anything to annoy or bother evil spirits</li>
<li>If you win a game doing a certain routine, don&rsquo;t change that routine as long as you continue winning</li>
</ul>


<p>The list goes on and on.  Superstitions, old wives' tales, and folklore.  By any of its names, luck abounds in all cultures.</p>

<p>I got to thinking about this because Chinese New Year happened a little while ago and brought <a href="http://go.gtww.net/1m7d6bk">red envelopes</a> with it.  It&rsquo;s interesting to be a Christian and Chinese at this time of year.  I shouldn&rsquo;t believe in luck, and yet I still accept these gifts which are filled with ideas of luck and prosperity.  (I&rsquo;ve come to accept it as a gift but heartily do not believe that it wards off evil spirits or brings me good luck.)</p>

<p>Luck, and all of its spawn, are everywhere.  It will take some effort to avoid allowing it to take hold in my life, that&rsquo;s for sure!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[When Selfishness Surpasses Logic]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/when-selfishness-surpasses-logic/"/>
    <updated>2013-12-07T11:10:32-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.goingthewongway.com/when-selfishness-surpasses-logic</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I was out for lunch on a Sunday afternoon in Chinatown.  The restaurant that my group went to was mostly full, but we were able to get a table in a back room.  It wasn&rsquo;t ideally placed since it was awkwardly positioned relative to another large table, but it was definitely better than having to wait.  I sat near the large table with my back to it and at some point later on in the meal my lunch mates indicated for me to look behind me.  Lo and behold there was an elderly Chinese woman sitting with her chair positioned so that I could not move back any further.  This wouldn&rsquo;t be a problem if that&rsquo;s what the proximity of our tables required, but she was so far from her table that she couldn&rsquo;t touch it if she wanted to.  In fact I&rsquo;m not sure if she could have touched the people who were sitting at the table!  She had taken it upon herself to reserve as much space for her table as possible.  Oh fantastic.</p>

<p>As we concluded and left our lunch, my group discussed this.  What amazed us most was the fact that she would make herself so uncomfortable to do what she did.  In the end, she was able to reserve some extra breathing room for her lunch mates even though she had put herself out of sorts.  However, the extra breathing room is pretty useless if you already have plenty of breathing room!  Ultimately I am losing, she is losing, and her tablemates are not really gaining anything of use.</p>

<p>In a small personal context this doesn&rsquo;t make sense.  Nor does it in a larger social sense.  Getting cheap/free healthcare is going to cost all of the rest of the people more (whether reduced benefits or higher cost).  For you to get more, others must get less.  There is no magic fountain of money and benefits.  Would you pursue more if ultimately getting more meant that everyone got nothing?  What if everything collapsed because everyone was getting something for free?  Was it worth it?  Is your pension worth it if governments go bankrupt?  Is it even worth anything at that point?</p>

<p>Take what you&rsquo;re doing and think about the consequences.  You might not like what you find.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Shopping Is Fun, Really!]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/shopping-is-fun-really/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-11T21:02:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.goingthewongway.com/shopping-is-fun-really</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>```python
items_in_store = getAllItems()</p>

<p>def shop_fast(user, items_to_buy):</p>

<pre><code>shopping_cart_items = []
for item in items_to_buy:
    item.find()
    if user.wants(item):
        shopping_cart_items.append(item)
for item in shopping_cart_items:
    user.buy(item)
</code></pre>

<p>def shop_slow(user, items_to_buy):</p>

<pre><code>shopping_cart_items = []
for item in items_in_store:
    if item in items_to_buy:
        print('Awesome!')
    if user.wants(item):
        shopping_cart_items.append(item)
for item in shopping_cart_items:
    user.buy(item)
</code></pre>

<p>if gender is &lsquo;Male&rsquo;:</p>

<pre><code>shop_fast(user, items)
</code></pre>

<p>else:</p>

<pre><code>shop_slow(user, items)
</code></pre>

<p>```</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Your Word]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/your-word/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-25T05:56:47-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.goingthewongway.com/your-word</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>```python</p>

<h1>trusting_others.py</h1>

<p>#</p>

<h1>How our words affect our interaction with others. You&rsquo;re only as good as your word!</h1>

<p>#</p>

<h1>Psuedocode:</h1>

<h1></h1>

<h1>Maintain list of trust that others have, which is unknown to you</h1>

<h1>Interact with people each day</h1>

<h1>Alter trust with your words</h1>

<h1>Trust quotient is a quantifier for one person&rsquo;s trust for another</h1>

<p>TRUST_REWARD = 1
TRUST_PENALTY = 15</p>

<h1>Dictionary containing name and trust quotient values that other people have for you</h1>

<p>trust = {}</p>

<p>for day in days:</p>

<pre><code>for person in interactions(day):
    if person not in trust:
        # Other people's trust depends on some variables 
        trust[person] = default_trust(person.upbringing, person.genes)

    if speak() == 'TRUTH':
        trust[person] += TRUST_REWARD;
    elif speak() == 'FALSEHOOD':
        trust[person] -= TRUST_PENALTY
</code></pre>

<p>```</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Telephone Problem]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/the-telephone-problem/"/>
    <updated>2011-10-12T01:44:56-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.goingthewongway.com/the-telephone-problem</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The game <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chinese_whispers">telephone</a> (although apparently its original name is a bit more offensive!) is a simple game that teaches us a valuable lesson.  From it we learn that people are awful at accurate transmission of information.  In the case of the game, it leads to amusement and fun when finding out how quickly and drastically words will change.</p>

<p>However the game is not as funny in its everyday depictions.  We reference people who reference other people who read about some research piece in a magazine.  Other people pass along hearsay as common knowledge, and we grow to have a distorted view of truth.  We might see these everyday ranging from <a href="http://lifehacker.com/5847591/10-stubborn-food-myths-that-just-wont-die">common myths about food</a> to <a href="http://www.boundless.org/2005/articles/a0001126.cfm">common myths about (unmarried couples) living together</a>.  Despite our best intentions at accuracy there is something that we will never learn from the telephone game as well as we should &ndash; we are just not able to effectively relate information.  It is somehow beyond our grasp.  We tend toward chaos simply because we are human.</p>

<p>(Then again that is why coming upon <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dead_Sea_Scrolls">exceptions </a>to this rule is so amazing!)</p>

<p>Lesson to be learned?  You cannot relay information well so do it more judiciously.  That is, information that you do not relay does not have the opportunity to prove that you are speaking falsely.  Don&rsquo;t trust me?  There are more <a href="http://www.biblegateway.com/passage/?search=Proverbs%2017:28&amp;version=NASB">reputable sources</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
