<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Life | Going The Wong Way]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/categories/life/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-10-15T22:25:22-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.goingthewongway.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Derek Wong]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Your Word]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/your-word/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-25T05:56:47-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.goingthewongway.com/your-word</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>```python</p>

<h1>trusting_others.py</h1>

<p>#</p>

<h1>How our words affect our interaction with others. You're only as good as your word!</h1>

<p>#</p>

<h1>Psuedocode:</h1>

<h1></h1>

<h1>Maintain list of trust that others have, which is unknown to you</h1>

<h1>Interact with people each day</h1>

<h1>Alter trust with your words</h1>

<h1>Trust quotient is a quantifier for one person's trust for another</h1>

<p>TRUST_REWARD = 1
TRUST_PENALTY = 15</p>

<h1>Dictionary containing name and trust quotient values that other people have for you</h1>

<p>trust = {}</p>

<p>for day in days:</p>

<pre><code>for person in interactions(day):
    if person not in trust:
        # Other people's trust depends on some variables 
        trust[person] = default_trust(person.upbringing, person.genes)

    if speak() == 'TRUTH':
        trust[person] += TRUST_REWARD;
    elif speak() == 'FALSEHOOD':
        trust[person] -= TRUST_PENALTY
</code></pre>

<p>```</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Telephone Problem]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/the-telephone-problem/"/>
    <updated>2011-10-12T01:44:56-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.goingthewongway.com/the-telephone-problem</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The game <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chinese_whispers">telephone</a> (although apparently its original name is a bit more offensive!) is a simple game that teaches us a valuable lesson.  From it we learn that people are awful at accurate transmission of information.  In the case of the game, it leads to amusement and fun when finding out how quickly and drastically words will change.</p>

<p>However the game is not as funny in its everyday depictions.  We reference people who reference other people who read about some research piece in a magazine.  Other people pass along hearsay as common knowledge, and we grow to have a distorted view of truth.  We might see these everyday ranging from <a href="http://lifehacker.com/5847591/10-stubborn-food-myths-that-just-wont-die">common myths about food</a> to <a href="http://www.boundless.org/2005/articles/a0001126.cfm">common myths about (unmarried couples) living together</a>.  Despite our best intentions at accuracy there is something that we will never learn from the telephone game as well as we should - we are just not able to effectively relate information.  It is somehow beyond our grasp.  We tend toward chaos simply because we are human.</p>

<p>(Then again that is why coming upon <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dead_Sea_Scrolls">exceptions </a>to this rule is so amazing!)</p>

<p>Lesson to be learned?  You cannot relay information well so do it more judiciously.  That is, information that you do not relay does not have the opportunity to prove that you are speaking falsely.  Don't trust me?  There are more <a href="http://www.biblegateway.com/passage/?search=Proverbs%2017:28&amp;version=NASB">reputable sources</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Inevitability Of Friendship]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/the-inevitability-of-friendship/"/>
    <updated>2011-08-11T01:50:24-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.goingthewongway.com/the-inevitability-of-friendship</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I like having friends.  They usually share some connection with you and are able to share in experiences with you.  Laughter, excitement, and life all happen when friends are around.</p>

<p>But something that I am continuing to learn is that friendships will change.  As in, you will change.  Or the friend(s) will change.  Or circumstances will change.  Maybe you just stopped trying.  Maybe they slighted you in some way.  All of this adds up to your friendship changing.</p>

<p>So apparently I am much worse than I thought I would be at maintaining friendships.  People have come and gone in my life.  Some have left a mark (and amusingly many have not).  Many are now gone.</p>

<p>Now looking back on times long gone, I realize how difficult it would have been to predict how my life would have turned out.  Even if things had been planned or more effort would have been invested, I know that it would have been quite difficult to overcome what has turned out to be the biggest reason for all of the change: <strong>life</strong>.</p>

<p>Proofreading this post I have come to the conclusion that this could have been written by a lovesick high school kid secretly talking about some girl he had a crush on who just stopped talking to him even though all indications were that she liked him.  Not that I have that experience, I'm just saying.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I Would Not Outsource My Projects]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/i-would-not-outsource-my-projects/"/>
    <updated>2011-04-19T01:22:53-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.goingthewongway.com/i-would-not-outsource-my-projects</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Have you heard of outsourcing?  Besides the TV show, there is much to the issue of outsourcing.  At the heart of it, outsourcing basically means getting someone else to do the work.  When used in terms of software, it usually refers to having someone overseas in India or China write the code according to what the desired behavior is.  For the past decade or so there has been talk (and more than talk) about how all of the software created is going to be outsourced rather than done in America.  In fact I remember during my undergraduate studies there was a survey taken of my class to find out whether talk of the outsourcing of our future careers scared us into going into other fields.  At the time it did not seem too pressing of an issue.  Maybe it is because we were not aware enough of what was really going on in the industry yet.  In any case, the reason that all of the outsourcing was talked about is basically because  American computer programmers are much more expensive than those in other countries.</p>

<p>So what does this mean to me (or you) unless you are getting laid off as your work is being moved overseas?  I think it still is quite relevant.  Because it is not just losing a job that causes me to stop.  It is really the fact that I have seen people purposely choose to outsource their own projects!   In their new ventures they have opted to outsource the programming to some other group or country.  As for me, though, I do not think that I would ever outsource my projects.</p>

<p>Reasons why I would not outsource my projects:</p>

<ul>
<li><p>I set out on a side project because <strong>I want to learn</strong> something.  Maybe I want to learn a new programming language.  Maybe I just want to go through the experience of building something in particular.  After all, <a href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/366/experience-matters/">experience matters</a>.  And I want that experience.</p></li>
<li><p>Outsourcing something essentially <strong>tramples upon the lower state of others</strong>.  While I am sure that I do this in an indirect way (e.g., by buying anything made in China), it still seems worse to me to directly order other people to do things.</p></li>
<li><p>When I do something myself, I get this odd <strong>satisfaction from doing something myself</strong>.  I do not imagine that everyone else feels the same way.  In fact I would guess that most other people just want whatever it is to work.  But I love being able to look at something (even if it is imperfect) and knowing that I had a huge hand in doing it.</p></li>
<li><p>There seem to be a myriad of reasons why working with people in another country (or even other people in general) would be difficult.  This includes things like <strong>language, time difference, and general misunderstandings</strong>.  As the sayings goes: "If you want something done right you have got to do it yourself."  Because trusting others to do things that you want to do is not ever going to work out just as you have planned.</p></li>
</ul>


<p>While people can (obviously) do whatever they want with their projects, I am pretty sure that I would not do such a thing.  In fact it flies in the face of who I want to be.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Experience Required]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/experience-required/"/>
    <updated>2010-10-16T01:15:03-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.goingthewongway.com/experience-required</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You might be surprised to know that I actually know that I do not know everything.  People who personally interact with me sure are.  Even more likely, they flat out refuse to believe it.</p>

<p>But I am confident that I am not delusional.  I know that I do not know everything.  So yes, I am confident when I think that I know something (<a href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/5/algorithm-for-your-life/">as most people are</a>), but I also have seen enough to know that there is a vast amount of things that I have no idea about.</p>

<p>When I was learning how to drive, I did not give too much credit to my parents when they told me that experience matters in determining how good of a driver I was.  I thought that as long as I knew and followed the correct procedures, I would be just fine.  But I was wrong.  Surprise, surprise; experience really does matter.</p>

<p>Having the chance to actually see and try things for yourself is priceless.  There is absolutely no substitute for experience.  It gives you a warranted confidence that you know and can handle whatever it is that you are doing again.  Experience involves getting up close and personal with tasks.  You get to see (and hopefully get through) hiccups.  You get to see the whole process through to the end and learn lessons from first-hand knowledge.</p>

<p>So when someone is giving me <a href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/781/unsolicited-advice/">unsolicited advice</a> about a project or task, my immediate response is needing to know whether they have actually done it themselves.  I do not want to know if they understand what to do, have seen it done by someone else, or have read manuals about it.  I want to know if that adviser has actually done it.  If so, they have some credibility in my mind.  If not, their words might as well be "Wah wah wah."</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
