<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Rant | Going The Wong Way]]></title>
  <link href="http://dwong.github.com/categories/rant/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://dwong.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-09-16T21:04:57-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://dwong.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Derek Wong]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Go Get Some Experience]]></title>
    <link href="http://dwong.github.com/go-get-some-experience/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-01T00:10:21-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://dwong.github.com/go-get-some-experience</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It is pretty easy to read about how to conceptually do something.  It is equally easy to read about how other people have actually done something.  It is an entirely different task to do that something.</p>

<p>Let's take <a href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/596/finishing-my-first-marathon/">running a marathon</a>.  It is often referenced in terms of doing something difficult with perseverance.  Yes it is true that it is difficult.  Yes it is true that you need some perseverance (some more so than others simply because they aren't as ready).  <em>Talking about it</em>, though, requires experience.</p>

<p>When I was younger I chafed at the idea that I could not understand something simply because I had not done it yet.  When I was learning how to drive a car I doubted my parents when they told me that I needed experience.  They essentially claimed that they were better at driving simply because they had done it longer than I have.  I reasoned that I understood the laws better than they, and in fact I probably had better reactions than they did.  So it seemed fairly reasonable that I could drive as well (if not better than) they could.  My how I was young and foolish!  (On a side note I must remember that being foolish is very often associated with being young.)</p>

<p>I have learned that yes, experience does matter.  Nobody buys a book about trading stocks from an author who has never traded stocks.  Nor does one buy a cookbook by someone who could not boil water.  Neither do I want to hear someone extol the virtues of running a marathon if they have not actually run a marathon.  Do you want to talk about running a marathon?  Then <strong>run a marathon</strong>!  It will give your words more weight.  Alternatively there are countless other examples that you could draw from to prove your point.</p>

<p>Experience does not linearly increases abilities, but I have come to appreciate that experience brings a measure of wisdom.  Oh that's just great, next thing I know I am going to start calling kids "sonny" and talk about the "good ol' days".</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Path More Easily Chosen]]></title>
    <link href="http://dwong.github.com/the-path-more-easily-chosen/"/>
    <updated>2011-07-02T01:34:40-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://dwong.github.com/the-path-more-easily-chosen</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Nowadays it is all the rage to get medical help to correct our weight loss.  From the LAP-BAND to gastric bypass to diet drugs, we as a society are looking for a way to get rid of those extra pounds hanging on our bodies.  I am not sure if I am just blessed to be able to do things that others cannot or if I really am seeing with clear vision, but it seems that people could do with choosing to do things correctly (albeit with more difficulty).  That is, they should diet and exercise instead of going for the quick fix.</p>

<p>It seems strange to me that the LAP-BAND will compare itself to diet and exercise by saying that diet and exercise do not work because people fail.  While I am sure that is true, that is not a particular reason why the LAP-BAND is better since that comparison is effectively saying that it is better for a person if they cannot choose to do something themselves.  On the other hand I think that people need to make that choice.  With freedom they have a responsibility to live with their choices.  I would not want another person telling me what I can and cannot do.  The most marked change is the one that comes from within when they <a href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/476/having-the-desire/">have the desire for change</a>.  They need to want it so badly that they actually get out and do something to enact that change.</p>

<p>The part that amazes me so much (and which is the impetus for this post) is that people who do end up getting medical help take pride in that.  How can you be proud that you resorted to get surgery to get skinnier??  Absurdity of absurdities!  Can you be <a href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/229/proud-of-nothing/">proud of things that you have no control over</a>?  Well...apparently people are.  Still, the fact that people are will always boggle my mind.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Soda Fountain Thief]]></title>
    <link href="http://dwong.github.com/soda-fountain-thief/"/>
    <updated>2011-03-29T01:10:56-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://dwong.github.com/soda-fountain-thief</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>What up guy at the soda fountain using your definitively clear plastic water cup in order to get some soda?   How are your ill-gotten gains?   Tasty I hope.</p>

<p>I am sure that you have a good reason for doing what you do.  The world has probably beaten and berated you.  You deserve some of this sweet nectar.  Besides, you figure that it is a chain restaurant, and the syrup water that you are taking is really only worth cents to them.  If you have a job it probably is not the one that you really want (I mean not everyone gets to sleep in, tell people what to do, and have no pressure on them whatsoever).  Or maybe you don't get paid as much as you know that you deserve (it must be because people don't understand how much you are worth).</p>

<p>Some people will never learn to have integrity <a href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/6/cheaters-4-life/">no matter what they are doing</a>.  Some people will sell it for a little cup of soda.  Then again <a href="http://www.biblegateway.com/passage/?search=gen%2025:29-34&amp;version=NASB">others have sold much more valuable things for not much more in return</a>.</p>

<p>So keep at it, sir.  I know that you will no matter what I say.  And good luck on that whole job of your dreams thing.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Everyone Needs A Soundtrack]]></title>
    <link href="http://dwong.github.com/everyone-needs-a-soundtrack/"/>
    <updated>2010-12-30T00:15:56-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://dwong.github.com/everyone-needs-a-soundtrack</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Books are great.  They take us to far away lands and on many adventures.  They stimulate the mind and imagination to explore things that have been or things that could be.  But alas they are a dying form of entertainment it seems.</p>

<p>Even with the advent of the digital book reader (such as the <a href="http://amzn.to/Nxod9r">Amazon Kindle</a>), many people are moving towards more quickly gratifying forms of entertainment.  We want games immediately on our iPhone (even if it gives us <a href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/710/iphone-attention-deficit/">ADD</a>), we don't want to waste a moment of possible entertainment so we watch videos in our cars, and we maintain the convenient connection with people through Facebook and <a href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/83/tweedle-dee-twitter-dumb/">Twittter</a> rather than actually interacting with them face-to-face.</p>

<p>Now it seems that lately people are progressing even further.  Many people cannot even walk around without rocking some tunes.  They do this when they're by themselves, with their family, or even with their friends!  While this seems to be more prevalent with teenagers, I have seen it with others as well.  Is it the incessant need to be entertained?  Is it the desire to shut out the world to live in one's own fantasy?  I daresay that while these might be true, it is actually because everyone simply wants to be the hero!</p>

<p>Movies always have a soundtrack, and it is especially apparent during the monumental scenes.  What kind of a movie would it be if there was not music playing as the hero rescues the captive while avoiding 2 dragons, 10 soldiers, and a huge boulder?!  The music helps the audience experience the emotion and excitement.</p>

<p>So kids these days.  They should be commended.  They just want to be the hero and do good in the world.  Or maybe they just need a jolt of extra emotion in their lives, which is probably good because many accuse them of a lack of passion.  In any case, maybe we should all just give a kid with headphones on a high five.</p>

<p><em>Unless, of course, they're playing the villain's track.</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Getting Paid Under The Table]]></title>
    <link href="http://dwong.github.com/getting-paid-under-the-table/"/>
    <updated>2010-08-05T01:53:23-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://dwong.github.com/getting-paid-under-the-table</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Lately I feel like I have been encountering people who are getting paid under the table, which means that they are being paid in a way that attempts to circumvent tax laws.  Basically whoever is paying them is not reporting that payment as wages and that means that they are not liable for their share of the tax to the government.  The person being paid has the benefit of also not being subject to tax for that payment amount, which effectively means that everyone is keeping more money for themselves.</p>

<p>Unfortunately there is a loser in this transaction.  And that loser is everyone else.  Everyone who <strong>does</strong> pay their taxes loses because:</p>

<ol>
<li>they could be paying less</li>
<li>they could receive more benefits if everyone paid their taxes</li>
<li>the national debt (which at the time of writing stands at over $13 trillion - <a href="http://www.brillig.com/debt_clock/">check it out</a>) could be lower</li>
</ol>


<p>Instead it is left to the taxpayers to pick up their slack.  Yes, even though they (the ones involved in this nefarious transaction) are likely working members of society who do not see themselves as being a burden (they are making their own money after all), their presence on the roads, need for protection (e.g., police, fire), and receipt of other benefits are proof that they have an impact on us.</p>

<p>Integrity?  Yeah why don't we go for that.  Or at the absolute very least, acknowledge and label black as black and white as white.  It is not something to be proud of (and neither is stealing lunch money from a child).</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
