<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Work | Going The Wong Way]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/categories/work/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-10-25T15:23:05-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.goingthewongway.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Derek Wong]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gdansk, Poland]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/gdansk-poland/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-20T00:12:39-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.goingthewongway.com/gdansk-poland</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I traveled to Gdansk, Poland in the dead of winter for work.  I was there during the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2012_European_cold_wave">2012 European Cold Wave</a>.  I mean you know it's bad if the Poles thought that it was especially cold!  The news broadcast warnings that they should notify the police if they saw people outside sleeping (because they might actually have been dead!).  A far cry from sunny southern California to be sure!</p>

<div class="galleria">
<a href="http://img.gtww.net/2012/02_Gdansk/03ae/Gdansk-9_53c820a.jpg"><img data-title="Light In The Darkness" data-description="" src="http://img.gtww.net/2012/02_Gdansk/03ae/Thumbs/Gdansk-9_60ac.jpg"/></a>
<a href="http://img.gtww.net/2012/02_Gdansk/03ae/Gdansk-1_ab03741.jpg"><img data-title="Old-style Polish Zur" data-description="Tawerna" src="http://img.gtww.net/2012/02_Gdansk/03ae/Thumbs/Gdansk-1_7bb6.jpg"/></a>
<a href="http://img.gtww.net/2012/02_Gdansk/03ae/Gdansk-2_3763b88.jpg"><img data-title="Colorful Buildings" data-description="" src="http://img.gtww.net/2012/02_Gdansk/03ae/Thumbs/Gdansk-2_1559.jpg"/></a>
<a href="http://img.gtww.net/2012/02_Gdansk/03ae/Gdansk-3_a226dda.jpg"><img data-title="Frozen!" data-description="Stara Motlawa River" src="http://img.gtww.net/2012/02_Gdansk/03ae/Thumbs/Gdansk-3_056d.jpg"/></a>
<a href="http://img.gtww.net/2012/02_Gdansk/03ae/Gdansk-4_310bb45.jpg"><img data-title="History Is Here" data-description="" src="http://img.gtww.net/2012/02_Gdansk/03ae/Thumbs/Gdansk-4_8d28.jpg"/></a>
<a href="http://img.gtww.net/2012/02_Gdansk/03ae/Gdansk-5_3dc2f6f.jpg"><img data-title="20 Degrees F" data-description="Down Jacket Required" src="http://img.gtww.net/2012/02_Gdansk/03ae/Thumbs/Gdansk-5_3cd4.jpg"/></a>
<a href="http://img.gtww.net/2012/02_Gdansk/03ae/Gdansk-6_0525234.jpg"><img data-title="Ice Inside" data-description="There is ice on the INSIDE of the windshield" src="http://img.gtww.net/2012/02_Gdansk/03ae/Thumbs/Gdansk-6_93fa.jpg"/></a>
<a href="http://img.gtww.net/2012/02_Gdansk/03ae/Gdansk-7_ac27876.jpg"><img data-title="Warm Fruit Tea" data-description="Brovarnia Gdansk" src="http://img.gtww.net/2012/02_Gdansk/03ae/Thumbs/Gdansk-7_44ed.jpg"/></a>
<a href="http://img.gtww.net/2012/02_Gdansk/03ae/Gdansk-8_26fa294.jpg"><img data-title="Repurposed Car" data-description="Brovarnia Gdansk" src="http://img.gtww.net/2012/02_Gdansk/03ae/Thumbs/Gdansk-8_3e9f.jpg"/></a>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Crom, The One Who Is All Up In Your Business]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/crom-the-one-who-is-all-up-in-your-business/"/>
    <updated>2011-09-15T01:20:31-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.goingthewongway.com/crom-the-one-who-is-all-up-in-your-business</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>People want their private space.  People <strong>need</strong> their private space.  Some people have even been known to go crazy without it!</p>

<p>Unfortunately there are people who do not seem to really understand the whole personal space thing.  My co-worker, Crom, is exactly one of those people.  I don't know if I would go so far as to say that he enjoys getting all up in people's business (and by business I mean personal space), but he definitely does it the majority of the time.</p>

<p>It's even worse for the short ones!  He is pretty tall (over 6') and has a bit of a portly stomach, which I would imagine would make shorter people feel like he is intruding into his space even more if his stomach is near their face!  Thankfully I am not at that height.  Interestingly enough <a href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/914/crom-the-one-with-the-girlfriend/">his girlfriend</a> <strong>is</strong> pretty short at (I'm estimating) 5'2".</p>

<p>The best part is getting to watch Crom do this to other people.  Unbeknownst to him, I observe him and amuse myself  with all of it.  What can you learn from all of this?  Beware of the watchful ones since they are probably analyzing and making fun of you in their head.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Crom, The One With The Girlfriend]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/crom-the-one-with-the-girlfriend/"/>
    <updated>2011-03-23T01:22:38-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.goingthewongway.com/crom-the-one-with-the-girlfriend</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The post title pretty much says it.  Crom, our (or at least my) favorite interesting co-worker, has a girlfriend.  While this may be new to you, it is not actually new information.  As far as I can gather they are in a long term relationship.  So that would probably make it pretty old information since my co-workers tell me that she's been in his life for awhile, and he has been here for 10 years.</p>

<p>So I wonder, what is it about commitment that scares people?  He is probably in his mid to late 40's, and from the sound of it has never been married while he has worked here.  I have heard him joke about getting married to his girlfriend.  Of course I would imagine that those jokes have happened many times over the years with no obvious change in the situation.  Maybe he's just testing things out like <a href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/825/crom-the-one-without-license-plates/">he's testing out his "new" car</a>.</p>

<p>I wonder if he writes a blog, and he wonders about me being a young (relatively to him) guy who has already gotten suckered into getting married.  Let's hope so!</p>

<p>The funniest part is that I could never forget her name.  Previously he gave some of us login information for one of his machines so that we could work on a project.  Her name was the password.  Even though I have long since worked on that project, I definitely keep that Post-It note around just for kicks.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I Don't Want Your Smoke]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/i-dont-want-your-smoke/"/>
    <updated>2011-02-21T00:07:55-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.goingthewongway.com/i-dont-want-your-smoke</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have a new coworker, and he smokes cigarettes.  I had no idea that I cared so much until he started his new job recently.  Now I have had coworkers who smoked in the past, but they were never close enough in proximity to make a huge difference to me.  That is I could smell the stench when I got close to them, but I did not need to be close to them to do my work on a regular basis.  However this new coworker is in the cubicle right next to me so suffice to say he is very close to where I need to be to do my work on a regular basis.</p>

<p>Everyday I find myself trying to figure out his smoking break schedule so that I can tell when I want to take a nice stroll around to see what everyone else is up to.  I find myself trying to cover my nose (even though I know that the third-hand smoke can easily get through whatever it is that I'm using to cover it).  Somehow, whether real or imagined into being, I find that sometimes I will feel slightly ill right around the time that he comes back from his smoke break.</p>

<p>The coworker does not help the situation very much because he is hardly friendly.  He pretty much keeps to himself even when everyone else is chatting.  He seems content to be in his world, and subsequently I do not really have a relationship with him.  He does not seem stupid so I am pretty sure that he is aware of all of the warnings about the detrimental effects of smoking.  At least he knows that he has to go outside to smoke.  In any case, I have been thinking about what I can do about this little problem.  Some ideas that I have had:</p>

<ul>
<li><p>Post a sign about smoking (which might get me onto <a href="http://www.passiveaggressivenotes.com/">Passive Aggressive Notes</a>)</p></li>
<li><p>Move all of his stuff to another cubicle far away and print out a paper directing him to his new location as a result of some hazard located only in his cubicle with thanks and regrets from "The Management"</p></li>
<li><p>Complain loudly to everyone except to him.  If he asks me about it then just deny, deny, deny</p></li>
<li><p>Get a fan (its size depending on how passive aggressive I'm feeling) and turn it on whenever he comes back from a smoke break</p></li>
<li><p>Complain to human resources that I am in an unsuitable environment</p></li>
<li><p>As soon as he gets back from his smoke breaks loudly take my laptop and stomp over to another cubicle or office to start working there</p></li>
</ul>


<p>Or I just realized that I <em>could</em> just you know...talk to him and tell him how I feel.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Crom, The One Who Cuts His Toenails At Work]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.goingthewongway.com/crom-the-one-who-cuts-his-toenails-at-work/"/>
    <updated>2010-07-28T01:19:54-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.goingthewongway.com/crom-the-one-who-cuts-his-toenails-at-work</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Snip, snip, snip.  The familiar sound can be heard at my workplace.  Imagine the surprise of myself and my coworkers as we were chatting when we heard it.  The sound is rather unmistakable and usually reserved for the bathroom in one's home.  However, we were actually at work on a weekday.</p>

<p>It came as little surprise to us that Crom would do this.  He is a man of little social reservation.  He is the first to (eagerly) get his food.  He is the first to go back to work so that he can leave earlier (without helping to clean up of course).  He talks (sometimes loudly I might add) on the phone with his girlfriend (as I understand it, it's a long term kind of thing).  Truthfully, I would not be awfully surprised if he picks his nose and eats whatever treasure he finds.</p>

<p>Once you hear your co-worker cutting his toenails at work, all bets are off.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
